（美國亞馬遜米高梅影片公司 出品）
（美國藝術家權益制片公司 制作）
好了 讓我來問問大家
Okay, let me ask you something.
（西班牙語）你們好嗎
?Qué pasa? Huh? ?Qué pasa, eh?
本次大獎將會花落誰家 你們來告訴我
Now, who's gonna win the money?
（美國華納兄弟影片公司）
Show me!
盡情享受游戲吧
It's time for fun right now.
誰會第一個喊出賓果
Who's gonna bingo?
游戲正式開始
Okay, let's get started right now.
今晚搖出的第一個號碼是
Here's the first ball.
I-17 《舞蹈皇后》也是十七歲
And it's gonna be I-17, the dancing queen.
今晚現場有多少個舞蹈皇后
How many dancing queens do we have out there tonight?
（賓果之夜）
好的
All right.
接下來是G-58
This is gonna be G-58,
“要我發”
make them wait.
? See-line woman ?
? She drink coffee ?
? She drink tea ?
? Then she go home ?
? See-line woman ?
? Dressed in green ?
? Wears silk stockings with golden seams ?
? See-line woman ?
? Dressed in red ?
? Make a man lose his head...
接下來是B-4
This is gonna be B-4,
寓意著“必勝”
knock at the door.
B-4
B-4,
寓意著“必勝”
knock at the door.
我已就位
On location.
發現目標
Eyes on.
目標朝小巷走去
Headed towards the alley.
（正在呼叫）
（伯克）
看到她了
She there?
對 她出現了
Oh, yeah, she's here.
金還在里面
And King's still inside?
沒錯 像只待宰的羊羔
He sure is, like a little lamb.
干得利索點 科布 兩個都是 明白嗎
I want the decks cleared, Cobb, both of them. Understood?
我就在這兒盯著 等著 然后和你匯報
Gonna watch, wait, and I'll report back, Burke.
下一個可能是你們的幸運球
? See-line woman ?
（薩爾瓦…）
號碼是G-56
It's gonna be G-56,
“都沒我牛”
was she worth it?
G-56
G-56,
“都沒我牛”
was she worth it?
N-41
? See-line woman ?
好了
我們的下一個球
讓我看看誰有這個號碼
有人說這號碼不吉利
但我覺得它很有意思
G-46 “急死咯”
快看 這邊很多人中了
Oh, oh, there. They've got lots of 'em over there.
（西班牙語）讓他們看看
N-41
N-41.
預示著“今晚我第一”
N-41 stands for "time for fun."
N-41 劃掉它
N-41.
下一個號碼是 B-85
你好 雷金
Hello, Ray King.
艾妮絲
Ana?s.
你好 請坐
Please, have a seat.
接下來我們繼續
這次的號碼是 N-37
“三七二十一”
你有活兒要找我干
You have a job for me?
是的
Yeah.
我有樣東西
Here, let me, uh...
照片上是
This is...
吉諾桑切斯和他妻子伊迪絲
...Gino and Edith Sanchez,
還有他們的兒子阿爾貝托
their son Alberto.
他們當年離開了薩爾瓦多 來到了美國
They left El Salvador to come to the U.S.
阿爾貝托現在應該有13歲了
Alberto would be 13 now.
他當年5歲
He's... he's five there.
我不殺小孩
I don't kill children.
什么
Don't what?
把你的助聽器調大點聲
Turn your hearing aid up.
我只殺成年人
I do adults.
-我不殺小孩 -不 你誤會了
- I don't kill children. - Yeah, no, no, no.
他們失蹤了
They disappeared.
我受雇找到他們
I was hired to find them.
雇主是伊迪絲的父親
By her father.
號碼51
Number 51...
我只是…
I just...
想找你幫我
I need you to help me.
你是唯一能解決這事的人
I mean, you're really the only person who can.
我現在基本處于半退休狀態
You see, I'm semiretired now,
我只接那些對我有意義的案子
and I'm only taking cases that mean something to me.
你要我怎么幫你 金
What do you want, King?
艾妮絲
Ana?s...
你知道“后天學者癥候群”是什么嗎
...do you know what acquired savant syndrome is?
不知道
No.
但我知道 外面有幾個男人
But I know there are men outside,
那些會睡在非洲和中東機場門口的男人
the kind that sleep at airport gates in Africa and the Middle East.
他們跟蹤的不是我
They didn't follow me.
好吧 他們是沖我來的
Okay, they're gonna come after me.
他們跟過來后 你趕緊走
When they do, get out of here.
? See-line woman dressed in red ?
? Make a man lose his head ?
? See-line woman...
該死的
Fuck.
? See-line woman ?
? Oh, no, no, no ?
? Oh... ?
? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah...
? See-line, see-line ?
? See-line ?
? See-line...
見鬼
Fuck me.
? She drink coffee ?
? She drink tea ?
? Then she go home ?
? See-line woman, see-line woman ?
? Dressed in green...
? Wears silk stockings with golden seams ?
? See-line woman, see-line woman ?
? Dressed in red ?
? Make this man lose his head ?
? Lose his head, lose his head ?
? See-line woman, see-line woman ?
見鬼
Fuck.
? See-line woman ?
? Dressed in red ?
? Make a man lose his head ?
? See-line woman ?
? Dressed in green ?
? Wears silk stockings...
? See-line woman ?
會計刺客2
本WEB版外掛字幕由  風吹來的那片云  雙語合并
麥迪娜副局長辦公室
Deputy Director Medina's office.
（金融犯罪執法局 弗吉尼亞州 維也納）
麥迪娜局長 洛杉磯警局找您
Director Medina, I have the LAPD on the phone for you.
好的 椅子到了
Okay. Uh, chairs?
到了 兩把赫爾曼米勒的 一把世楷的
Yeah, two Herman Millers and a Steelcase.
謝謝
Thanks.
（金融犯罪執法局）
我是瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜
This is Marybeth Medina.
是的
Yeah.
等等 什么 再說一遍
Wait, what? Repeat that.
請描述下他的特征
Describe him, please.
不
No.
我明白
I understand.
（加利福尼亞州 洛杉磯）
他沒跟你說他在調查什么案子嗎
He didn't share what he was working on with you?
沒有
No.
我知道他掛出了私家偵探的招牌
Uh, I knew he put up a P.I. shingle,
但我們沒有聯絡
but we fell out of touch.
據你所知 他有財務問題嗎
So no money problems that you're aware of?
沒有
No.
就在那邊
Here, come this way.
雷蒙德金
Raymond King.
他是金融犯罪執法局前副局長
He was deputy director of FinCEN.
我的上司
My boss.
你說他身上什么都沒有 錢包也沒有嗎
You said they didn't find anything on him, no wallet?
可能本來有吧
Well, he might have.
但我們趕過去花了點時間
But it took us a little while to get there.
東西很可能在這期間遺失了
Things have a tendency of disappearing.
你們怎么會打給我的
Well, how'd you know to call me?
他的手機
His cell phone.
緊急聯絡人的名字寫的是你
You were his "in case of emergency" contact.
你剛才為什么問我他的財務問題
Well, why'd you ask if he was having money problems?
（找到那個會計師）
（愛達荷州 博伊西）
What's the difference between
精致休閑和商務休閑有什么區別
dressy casual and business casual?
兩個都意味著
Both mean leave your cargo shorts
你不能穿工裝短褲和人字拖出門
and flip-flops at home.
我沒有工裝短褲 也沒有人字拖
I don't own cargo shorts, and I don't own flip-flops.
現在可以談正經事了嗎
Could we discuss business now,
還是你需要更多第一次約會的建議
or do you need more first-date tips?
說吧
Go.
稻川會希望你在他們接管一家銀行之前
The Inagawa-kai want you to audit a bank before
對其進行審計
they assume control.
你怎么看
Thoughts?
你在東京太顯眼了
You're very conspicuous in Tokyo.
但是呢
But?
但是黑幫每次都會按時付錢
The yakuza always pay on time.
下一個
Next.
奧布雷貢先生想知道
Se?or Obregon wants to know
我們想要現金支付還是藝術品
if we want payment in cash or artwork.
他有什么藝術品
What art does he have?
一幅里維拉的畫作 他說你很喜歡
A Rivera he says you admired.
（私密號碼來電）
他欠我們多少
How much does he owe?
240萬
2.4 million.
當然選里維拉了
The Rivera, of course.
長嘆一口氣
Heavy sigh.
剩下應收賬款還有多少
What's the remainder of the receivables?
135萬
1.35 million.
分批打到新西蘭和法國的各個賬戶
Layer the rest in the New Zealand accounts and in France,
剩下的打到哈伯基金會
and the remainder in Harbor's endowment.
用哪個名字 高斯 巴貝奇 還是卡洛威
Under what name? Gauss, Babbage or Carroll?
納什 還有別的嗎
Nash. Anything else?
別穿你那件黑西裝
Don't wear your black suit.
那樣會看起來像個殯葬師
It makes you look like a mortician.
（子午線酒店及套房）
歡迎各位來到第13屆
Well, welcome to the 13th annual
“愛在博伊西”浪漫相親節的現場
Boise Romance Festival.
好耶
Whoa.
（愛在博伊西 浪漫相親節）
你們來這里只為了一個原因
You all are here for one reason:
找到緣分 遇見那個對的人
to make a connection, meet that special someone
（安）
邂逅你們的真愛
and find love.
對了
Oh, P.S.
（達爾比）
別忘了領取免費的相親節紀念T恤哦
Don't forget to pick up your free Romance Festival T-shirt.
（卡拉）
-價值25美元哦 -是的
- A $25 value there. - Yeah.
（安德莉亞）
你們大多數人都是第一次參加
So, since most of you are first-timers,
所以我們重新介紹下活動
let's recap how this works.
你們之前回答了一系列問題
You answered a battery of questions
這是為了體現出你們的喜好 需求
designed to express your wants, needs,
期待和渴望
hopes and desires.
然后 通過我們獨家的數學算法
We then used our proprietary mathematical algorithm
就能夠為你們找到最匹配的10個對象
to search for your ten best fits.
而在之前12次活動中
That same algorithm
我們的這套獨家算法已經成功促成了
in 12 previous festivals has resulted in...
53對有緣人喜結連理
53 marriages!
沒錯 掌聲鼓勵一下
All right, give it up for that.
厲害
Hell yeah.
現在 你們手中沒有對方的名字
Uh, now, no names were sent to you.
只有號碼牌和照片
Only the I.D. numbers and photos
是按照匹配程度排序的
ranked in order of connectivity.
不可以提前在網上搜索哦
No early online searches allowed.
每次約會限時五分鐘
You'll each spend five minutes per date,
之后是不限時自由交流環節
then unlimited time later in the day.
姑娘們
Oh, ladies,
今天不是比誰更快
it's-it's not a competition.
你們有足夠的時間趕到第一個約會地點
No, there's plenty of time to get to your first date last.
別這么心急
Hold your horses.
好吧 開始吧
Um, o-okay.
去找那個對的人吧
Go ahead, go on. Go meet that special someone.
-上帝保佑你們 不管你是不是教徒 -是的
- Godspeed. Nondenominational. - Yes.
嗨 你好
- Hi. - Hello.
我叫安蕾妮
Um, I'm Ann Renee.
我非常非常喜歡會計師
And I just love, love, love accountants.
-那真是太巧了 -是啊
- Well, that's a coincidence. - Yeah.
你相信一見鐘情這種事嗎
Um, do you believe in love at first sight,
有一天會遇到那個命中注定的人
that there's someone we're meant to be with,
所謂的 靈魂伴侶
a soulmate?
我不信這個 這想法太荒謬而且幼稚
Well, no, that's a... absurd, childish notion.
絕不可能發生
Of-of course that's not real.
什么叫你反向破解了我們的算法
What do you mean, you reverse-engineered our algorithm?
我對頭部約會軟件做了數據挖掘
I data-mined the top online dating apps
并比對了你們的問題
and mapped a battery of your questions against theirs.
（芭芭）
然后呢
And?
我自己建了套算法
I built my own dating algorithm.
關于愛情究竟是真實存在的 又或者
Well, the question of whether or not
只不過是人腦中
there's such a thing as love or it's simply an electrical,
所發生的神經電化學反應過程
- neurochemical process that takes place in the brain is up
還有待討論
for debate.
祝你一切順利
Uh, have a good day.
我從數據組中抓取了
I scraped the data clusters for
最有可能的約會觸發詞
the likeliest date-producing words.
等等 你說“約會觸發詞”
Wait. "Date-producing words"?
沒錯
Yes.
比如女人總說自己看重承諾和安穩
For example, women claim to value commitment and stability,
但又總愛選危險刺激的對象
but they swipe for dangerous and exciting.
性感壞男孩
Sexy bad boys.
嗨
Hi.
你好嗎
How are you?
我很好
Um, I'm doing really well.
-駱洛 -對 駱洛
- Lori. - Yeah, Lori.
這個是小名 還是綽號
Is that a nickname or short for anything?
不 我姓駱名洛
No, it's just Lori.
我通過在嵌入矩陣中對你們的問題分詞
I assigned numerical values to your questions by tokenizing them
為問題賦予數值
in an embedding matrix
并且針對最有效的答案
and generating a predictive model
生成了一個預測模型
for the most effective answers,
答案是我提供的
which I provided
不會撒謊
without lying.
我上一任男朋友
My last boyfriend
他每周末都和朋友打高爾夫球
spent every weekend golfing with his friends.
你會經常和朋友在一起嗎
Do you spend a lot of time with friends?
不 完全不會 不會
No, not at all. No.
我沒有朋友
I have no friends.
一個也沒有
No friends.
那…
Um,
寵物呢
pets?
我發現約會軟件里被投訴最多的
I identified misleading profile photos
就是照片和真人不符
as the top complaint across all dating apps.
女人在體重和年齡上撒謊
Women lie about weight and age.
而男人則是在身高和年齡上撒謊
Men lie about height and age.
所以我調整了我的照片和微笑方式
So I adjusted my photo and smile accordingly.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我喜歡露營 超喜歡
I like camping.
-我也是 -沒錯
- A lot. - So do I.
我好像在照片里看到有輛清風房車
Yeah, I thought I saw an Airstream in one of your photos?
沒錯 那是我的家
Yes, that's my home.
我住的地方
That's where I live.
永遠住下去
Oh, permanently?
除非我死了
Well, as long as I'm alive.
畢竟我們誰都沒法永遠住在一個地方
None of us are living anywhere permanently.
肉體也只是個軀殼
- Okay. - This is just a husk.
它最終會變成一具尸體
- Okay. Oh. - Eventually, this body will be a corpse.
而最棒的是
And the best part is
你不用再因為未申報的折舊
you don't have to amend your tax return
去修改報稅單了
for unclaimed depreciation,
這點有多么重要 我想你肯定清楚
which I'm sure you know is very meaningful.
這不僅會給你帶來意想不到的好處
Not only does it have that unintended benefit,
而最棒的是
but the best part is
你不用再因為未申報的折舊
that you don't have to amend your tax return
去修改報稅單了
for unclaimed depreciation.
我很愿意跟你分享 盡管嚴格來說
And I will share this with you even though it's a...
這算得上是商業機密了
well, it's a bit of a trade secret,
雖然不是什么專利
albeit not a proprietary one, but the best part is that
但最棒的是 你不用再因為未申報的折舊
you don't have to amend your tax return
去修改報稅單了
for unclaimed depreciation.
好吧
Yeah, um,
聊點別的吧
how about something else?
孩子
Um, kids?
你44歲
You're... 44?
45歲
Um, 45.
好吧 任何事都有可能嘛
Well, I suppose anything's possible.
天啊
Ugh. God.
至少從數學角度來說
I just mean mathematically.
你操縱了整個系統
You gamed the system?
我優化了我的個人資料
I optimized my profile.
整面墻從上到下都貼滿了
Whole wall covered top to bottom.
沒見過這么瘆人的
Damnedest thing you ever saw.
地圖 便簽條 變態照片
Maps, Post-it Notes, sicko photos.
就像是那個…
Like something
-《獵捕變態狂》節目里的場景 -沒錯
out of one of those "let's catch us a pervert" shows.
他真是有夠忙的
Busy little bee, wasn't he?
他的遺物你們怎么處理的
Wh-What did you do with his stuff?
我們沒扔掉
Oh, we didn't throw it away.
不收掉那些惡心的照片根本別想租出去
Couldn't rent it like that, all those nasty photos he had.
他在這兒住了多久
How long was he here?
兩個月
Two months.
昨天該付下期租金的
Next payment was due yesterday.
（概覽-2024年）
（哈伯神經科學學院 哈里斯米勒醫學博士 神經學教授）
（克里斯蒂安沃爾夫）
房租多少錢
The rent-- how much?
（哈伯神經科學學院 新罕布什爾州 漢諾威）
哈伯神經科學學院
Harbor Neuroscience Academy.
你好 我是美國財政部的麥迪娜副局長
Yeah, this is, uh, Deputy Director Medina, U.S.
你們有沒有
Treasury Department.
一個叫克里斯蒂安沃爾夫的員工
Is there a Christian Wolff on staff?
抱歉 女士 沒有
I'm sorry, ma'am. No.
好的
Okay.
那有沒有叫卡爾高斯的
Um, how about a Carl Gauss?
或者查爾斯巴貝奇
Or-or Charles Babbage?
路易斯卡羅爾 又或者叫盧
Lewis Carroll? Lou, maybe?
這里是哈伯神經科學學院
This is Harbor Neuroscience Academy.
是的 這點我知道
Yeah, I'm-I'm aware of that. Uh...
那你們有沒有
do you have any employees,
帶有英國口音的女性職員
maybe female, British accent?
您究竟想問什么
What's this in reference to?
你們之前有名學生 他父親曾是軍人
About a former student whose father was in the military?
學生檔案都被封存了
The student records are sealed.
我只是值班人員
Uh, I'm the after-hours receptionist.
您還是明天打來吧
You should probably call back tomorrow
那時會有人解答您的問題
when there's someone here who can answer that for you.
我要和那個會計師的聯絡人談談
I need to talk to the handler of The Accountant.
我知道她在聽
I know she's listening,
而那個會計師也會聽她的
and I know he listens to her.
您說什么
Excuse me?
我叫瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜
My name is Marybeth Medina.
我眼前有一大堆兇殺案的照片
I'm staring at a pile of homicide photos,
中美洲和墨西哥的地圖
maps of Central America,
一堆披薩收據 另外
Mexico, pizza receipts, and...
我敢肯定 還有一張她老板的照片
I'm pretty sure I'm staring at a photo of her boss.
我需要他的幫助
I need his help.
（加利福尼亞州 洛杉磯）
我要掛電話了
Hanging up now.
等等
W-Wait.
（已鎖定通話位置）
雷金被殺了
Ray King has been murdered.
（哈伯神經科學學院）
好了 讓我看看
Okay, let's see.
10塊 8塊 這個給你7塊
Ten, eight. Give you seven.
10塊 8塊 7塊一磅嗎
Ten, eight and seven? A pound?
一磅
Yeah, a pound.
這是壽司級的金槍魚
It's sushi-grade tuna.
得了吧 不是壽司級的
Oh, come on. It's not sushi-grade.
伯克 這是壽司級的
Burke, it's sushi-grade.
有碰傷 連脂肪都沒有
It's bruised. There's no fat on it.
根本不是壽司級的好嗎
It's not sushi-grade at all. Come on.
賣不賣隨你
Take it or leave it.
迪克在里面嗎
Dickie inside?
迪克在里面
Dickie's inside.
他會像上周和上上周一樣把錢給你的
He'll give you your money like last week and the week before,
老混蛋 行吧 行吧
you fucker. Yeah, yeah.
托尼 過來下
Tony, come on!
坐下吧
Sit down.
好了 說說
Okay, okay.
四個職業殺手卻干不掉一個女人
Four pro hitters couldn't take out one woman.
怎么會發生這種事
How is that possible?
嚴格說是兩個殺手
Technically, two hitters.
兩個對付金 兩個對付她
Two went after King. Two took her.
是三個 算上你
Three. Counting you.
我當時位置不好
I didn't have a clean shot.
你覺得她知道我們在追殺她而不是金嗎
You think she knows we were after her instead of King?
不可能
No chance.
你怎么知道
How you figure?
因為我們都還活著
We're aboveground.
那問題解決了
Problem solved.
按你自己說的
By your own logic,
如果她想殺你 你早就沒命了
if she wanted to kill you, she would have.
放松點 老板
Relax, boss.
她不記得你了
She don't remember you.
暫時
Yet.
這話是什么意思
The fuck does that mean?
幾年前她曾經出現過
She showed up a couple of years ago.
當時有三個家伙在和我談生意
The three men I was negotiating with had pissed
他們惹錯了對象
off the wrong people.
現在來談談 我們的偉大計劃
So, let's talk about our success.
你的大船
Your ships,
我的小船
my boats.
距離海岸20英里
20 miles out to sea, hmm?
別在洛杉磯港口就行 就選…
No Los Angeles port.
嘿
Just...
她沒認出你嗎
And she didn't recognize you?
沒有
No.
但總有一天她會想起我是誰 我做過什么
But one day she'll remember who I am and what I did,
等到那時候
and my whole world turns
我就完蛋了
to shit.
你給我飛去沃斯堡 今晚就走
You fly to Fort Worth tonight.
-別再出現第二個雷金 -收到
- No more Ray Kings. - Okay.
我不想再看到什么私家偵探
No more private investigators.
我可不想有一天從浴室出來
I don't want to get out of the shower one day
看到有人拿著電鋸在那兒等著我
and find a human chain saw waiting for me.
好的
Okay.
（電梯 出口）
（阿瓦拉多酒店）
我剛才大聲咳了兩下
I coughed loudly twice.
不 請不要這樣
No, please don't do that.
你是克里斯蒂安沃爾夫
You're Christian Wolff.
你是瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜
You're Marybeth Medina.
我讓你緊張了嗎
Do I make you nervous?
你是個越獄犯
You're an escaped convict,
還是黑幫會計師的徒弟
trained by a mob accountant.
你的客戶全是販毒集團
Your clients are drug cartels,
洗黑錢的 第三世界的軍閥
money launderers, third-world warlords.
所以你緊張了
Is that a yes?
我有看過你在布魯克林殺人的視頻
I saw a video of you killing men in Brooklyn.
八年前我在芝加哥
I was in Chicago eight years ago.
和雷一起
With Ray.
靈動機器人公司
Living Robotics.
我看到那些尸體 聽到你念那首童謠
I saw all the dead bodies, heard the chanting.
“所羅門格蘭迪 星期一降人世”
"Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday."
有什么能幫你的 麥迪娜女士
What can I do for you, Ms. Medina?
你喜歡拼圖嗎 沃爾夫先生
Do you like puzzles, Mr. Wolff?
我不知道這是一個還是十個案子
I don't know if this is one case or ten.
但我知道雷就快破產了
I do know Ray was nearly broke.
那張照片是我
I found that photo
在雷被殺那晚
in between the seat cushions
去過的酒館的坐墊夾縫中發現的
at the tavern Ray was at the night he was killed.
另外還有三個人在酒館里被槍殺
Three men were also shot to death inside the tavern,
還有一個是在酒館外被車撞死的
one struck by a car outside.
全都是前智利特種部隊
All ex-Chilean special forces,
勞塔羅特別行動旅的
Lautaro Brigade.
雷有這個本事嗎
Was Ray capable of that?
不 他沒有
No, he was not.
迪米特里約申科
Dmitry Yoshenko.
在莫斯科一家酒店被割喉
Throat slit in a Moscow hotel.
摩西約茨 耶路撒冷 死于汽車炸彈
Moshe Yeutz, car bomb, Jerusalem.
其余還沒確認身份
We haven't I.D.'d the rest.
阿曼多雷耶斯 墨西哥城
Armando Reyes, Mexico City.
奧贊烏納爾 伊斯坦布爾
Ozan Unal, Istanbul.
桑提諾桑維埃里 那不勒斯
Santino Sanvieri, Naples.
摔得真夠慘的
Must have been quite the fall.
摔下來并不會死
The fall didn't kill him.
最后停下反而會死
It was the abrupt stop.
是個笑話
It's a joke.
你為什么要幫我
Why are you helping me?
因為你讓我幫你
Because you asked me.
（得克薩斯州 沃斯堡）
（西班牙語）我們的天父 愿你受贊美
（西班牙語）以耶穌基督的名義祝福這食物
（西班牙語）阿門 阿門 阿門
Amen, amen, amen, amen.
現在情況是
Okay, so we've got
一共有四個雇傭兵躺在停尸房里
four dead mercs in the morgue,
多起兇殺案
homicides,
納稅申報表
tax returns,
墨西哥地圖 火車時刻表
map to Mexico, train schedule,
披薩 魚
pizza, fish,
家庭合照
family photo
還有一輛撞爛的豐田
and a trashed Toyota.
所以 到底要怎么把它們串聯起來呢
So, how does this all connect?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
等待
Waiting.
等什么
For?
等你結束
Well, for you to finish.
結束什么
Finish what?
我不知道
I don't know.
反正就是…
Um, whatever it is that, um...
你現在在做的事情
that you're in the process of doing.
然后你要
So you can...?
做我該做的事
Do what I need to do.
建議你看看醫生 解決打呼的問題
You might seek medical attention for the snoring problem.
咖啡要嗎
Coffee?
我不打呼嚕 所以…
I don't snore, so...
上面的位置全動過了
Nothing's where it was.
你的大腦 多數人的大腦
Well, your brain-- most brains--
在面對模糊的視覺數據時
when confronted with ambiguous visual data,
都會下意識地以一種熟悉的模式排列
seek subconsciously to arrange it in a pattern that's familiar,
但那不是我們要找的模式
but that's not the pattern we're looking for here.
沒錯 好吧
Right. Okay.
那我們要找的是什么模式
What-what pattern are we looking for?
存活概率
Survival probability.
他們的起點
They started...
在這兒 中美洲
...here, Central America.
好的
Okay.
你怎么知道的
How do we know that?
他的文身
His tattoo.
十八街幫是薩爾瓦多伊薩爾科監獄里
Barrio 18, Izalco Prison, El Salvador.
MS-13幫派的死對頭
They're at war with MS-13.
到達墨西哥邊境時 他們上了這列車
When they reached the border of Mexico, they boarded this train.
不 那是貨運列車 不是客運列車
Well, uh, no, that's a freight train, not a passenger train.
是死亡列車
It's the Death Train.
一家人趴在車頂上 而不是坐在車廂里
Families ride on the roof, not in the cars.
但這能避開移民檢查
It's the surest way to avoid immigration checkpoints.
當到達墨西哥城時
When they arrived at Mexico City,
他們會前往這三個地區中的一個
they would've typically headed to one of three areas
以便進入美國的得克薩斯州
to cross into Texas and the United States:
埃爾帕索 德爾里奧 麥卡倫
El Paso, Del Rio, McAllen.
他們選的是渡過格蘭德河進入麥卡倫
In this case, they crossed the Rio Grande into McAllen.
為什么是麥卡倫
Why McAllen?
1加侖水重達8磅 想在沙漠里生存
A gallon of water weighs eight pounds. A human being requires between one
一個人每天得要1.5到2加侖的水
and a half and two gallons of water a day to survive in the desert.
也就是每人要帶36到48磅的水
So that's 36 to 48 pounds
這還不算帶著一個5歲的孩子
a person not carrying a five-year-old has to carry.
這是她5歲的兒子
Here's her son at five.
在這張照片里 他大概13歲
In this photograph, he looks to be about 13.
伊迪絲來到洛杉磯找了份工作
Edith arrived in Los Angeles and claimed work
（蘇迪奧披薩店）
在蘇迪奧披薩店打工
at Sudio's Pizza.
等等 哪個伊迪絲
Uh, h-hold on. Um, Edith?
伊迪絲桑切斯
Edith Sanchez.
不 你憑什么能夠確定
No, you can't possibly know
這張照片里的女人就是這張
that this woman in the photo
納稅申報表上的這個伊迪絲桑切斯
is the same Edith Sanchez on these 1040s.
不 我能確定
Yes, it's a certainty.
她申報需撫養一個孩子
She claimed one dependent, a child.
而她的三份申報表中
Of the three 1040s she filed, two had incomes
有兩份收入約為15000美元
of roughly $15,000.
第三份是60250美元
The third was $60,250.
這可比前兩年的收入加起來還要多一倍
That's twice as much in one year than the previous two combined.
對 這還不是最奇怪的
Yes. That's not the strangest part.
她選了“已婚” 但卻單獨報稅
She checked "married" but filed separately.
如果選擇聯合報稅
Had she filed jointly, she could've taken advantage
還能享受照料子女的抵免
of the child and dependent care exemption.
第三年收入暴增四倍
Four times as much money in the third year,
選了已婚卻單獨報稅
checks "married," files separately,
有孩子卻沒相關費用
has a child and no child care.
雷過去一年半的客戶名單上有六個人
A list of Ray's clients over the last 18 months shows six names,
只有一個是拉丁裔姓氏
only one with a Latino surname:
埃米利亞諾 埃米岡薩雷斯
Emiliano "Emi" Gonzalez,
得克薩斯州沃斯堡
Fort Worth, Texas.
（埃米利亞諾岡薩雷斯）
所以如果
So, if
埃米就是伊迪絲的父親
Emi was Edith's father,
她為何不找她父親
why didn't she call him for help?
這就不知道了
I have no way of knowing that.
在國稅局有人脈嗎
Do you have any influence at the IRS?
（蘇迪奧披薩店 加利福尼亞州 英格爾伍德）
給我盯著點裝卸區
Keep an eye on the loading dock.
怎么有那么多彪形大漢
What's with the muscle?
你肯定沒怎么在洛杉磯待過吧
You don't spend much time in Los Angeles, do you?
我可不想被人拿著槍搶劫
I'm not a fan of getting pistol-whipped and robbed.
不 我不記得有叫伊迪絲的
No, I don't remember any Edith.
抱歉 我幫不了你們
Sorry. Can't help you.
珍妮特 要簽什么
Jeanette, what do you got?
看起來不錯 謝謝
- Looks great. - Mm-hmm.
為什么一個員工會無故放棄
Why would an employee not take all
她本該享有的稅收減免
the exemptions she's eligible for?
因為她很蠢
'Cause she's dumb?
因為她跟你不一樣
'Cause she doesn't look like you?
都不是
Neither one.
在我這兒 人不分合法或不合法
Well, I don't see people as legal or illegal.
我把他們當人看 所以給他們機會
I see 'em as human beings, and I give 'em a chance.
還有別的事嗎
Anything else?
沒了 先生 耽誤你了
No, sir. Thanks for your time.
不客氣
You're welcome.
你三分之二的生意是外賣 對吧
Two thirds of your business is takeout, correct?
你們查了我的稅務報表哈
Got my tax reports, huh?
你們這些家伙
You people.
沒錯 三分之二
That's right-- two thirds.
你盡管問 單位成本 工資單 促銷活動
Ask me anything. Unit costs, payroll, promotions.
隨便問 每分錢的去向我都一清二楚
You name it, I know where every dime goes.
去年未計利息 稅項 折舊及攤銷前的利潤
Last year's earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization.
4290萬
42.9 mil.
你報的是4190萬
You claimed 41.9 million.
看仔細點 財務專家
Keep reading, EF Hutton.
其中100萬我捐給了流浪者收容所
A million in charitable contributions to homeless shelters.
我們走吧
Let's go.
拋開這份稅表做得有多業余不說
Setting aside the amateur nature of this preparation,
你其實可以從應納稅收入中
considering you could've deducted
扣除更多費用
considerably more from your taxable income,
最常被點的披薩尺寸是多大
what is the most frequently ordered size of pizza?
大號的 占90%
Large, 90%.
大號披薩售價17.35美元
Large pizza is $17.35,
也就是1,484,315個大號披薩
which accounts for 1,484,315 large pizzas.
你想說什么
What's your point?
你的紙張成本是36萬美元
Your paper costs are $360,000,
而這些錢只夠你做90萬個大號披薩盒
which only accounts for 900,000 large pizza boxes.
你說得我頭都大了
You are making my head hurt.
這比前面提到的
It's considerably less than the aforementioned
1,484,315個大號披薩要少很多
1,484,315 large pizzas.
對 那是因為我們切開賣
Right, that's because, uh, we do it by the slice.
切開賣 不 不可能
- By the slice? No. - Yeah.
你謊報比實際更多的收入是為了
Impossible. You're fraudulently claiming more income than you're receiving
隱瞞其他收入來源 是什么
in order to conceal income from another source. What is it?
你這個混蛋
You fucking rodent.
你先等一下
Now, wait just a second.
我在百忙之中抽出時間來 回答你愚蠢的問題
I take time out of my busy day to answer your silly-ass questions,
而你現在居然敢在這里指控我洗黑錢
and you got the balls to accuse me of money laundering?
克里斯
Chris!
該死
你就是在洗錢
You're laundering money.
-那些錢是從哪里來的 -放開我的胳膊
- Where is it coming from? - Let go of my arm!
聯邦探員 往后退 這里沒事
Federal agent! Stay back. Everything's fine.
你在洗錢 告訴我錢的來源
You're washing money. Tell me where it's coming from,
否則我會卸掉你的肩膀
or I will dislocate your shoulder.
-滾開 你個混蛋 -疼得很
- Fuck off, you motherfucker. - It's quite painful.
克里斯 夠了
Chris, that's enough!
-我提醒過你的 -不
I told you.
該死的 我沒有販賣那些女孩
I don't traffic those girls!
我對天發誓 我接到個電話
No, I-I swear to God, I get a call.
我接到個電話 錢就來了
I get a call, the cash comes in.
我知道他們常去的兩家汽車旅館
I know where they they use a motel or two.
-一間套房 -他們是誰
- A suite. - Who is "them"?
我不知道 你去問那些女孩
I-I don't know. Ask one of the girls.
哪家汽車旅館
What motel?
-哪家汽車旅館 -市中心的城市中心旅館
- What motel? - City Center, Downtown.
聯絡人是誰
Who's your contact?
拜托 不要
Please, no.
聯絡人是誰
Who's your contact?
托馬斯
Tomas!
我們該走了
We should go.
你小時候摔壞過腦子嗎
Were you dropped on your head as a child?
我覺得這不是你真正想問的
I feel that's not really your question.
知道嗎 我為政府部門工作
You know, I work for a government agency.
我不會嚴刑拷打別人
I don't torture people.
你確實沒有
You didn't.
身為金融犯罪執法局的副局長 我…
I'm the deputy director of FinCEN, so I can't...
我知道 多虧我
I know. I put you there.
你和雷金都是
You and Ray King.
有個英國女人打來 不斷地給我線索
You know, a British woman calls and gives me tips.
所以罪犯 也就是你們
So criminals-- which is what you are--
給執法人員 也就是我
give law enforcement-- that's me--
每天提供線索
tips every day.
如果你說的線索是指姓名 日期 行為
If by "tips" you mean names, dates, acts,
銀行賬戶 清算號碼
account numbers, routing numbers,
沒錯 是我提供的
yes, I give you tips.
我跟你不一樣
You know, I'm not like you.
我不會隨心所欲地犯法
I can't just break the law when it suits me.
不準再使用暴力
No more violence.
我們得順著他給的線索 找到幕后主使
We need to take what he gave us and work our way up the chain.
這才是正確的方法
That's how this is done.
也許局里能抽調一個本地探員來支援我們
Maybe the Bureau has an agent in this office they can spare.
我有個人選
I may know someone.
（德國 柏林）
（德語）搞定 非常好
（德語）這是您的房卡 頂樓的總統套房
（德語）這里還有留給您的一個盒子
（德語）給您
（德語）還有什么可以效勞的嗎
（德語）謝了
（德語）電梯在左手邊 祝您愉快
（德語）回頭見
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
嘿 瑪格麗特 是我
Hey, Margaret, it's...
瑪格麗特 瑪… 嗨
Margaret...
嘿
Hey.
咦 太假了 拜托
Fucking come on.
嗨 瑪格麗特 是我布萊斯頓
Hi, Margaret. It's Braxton.
你好 嗨
Hello. Hi.
你好 瑪格麗特
Hello, Margaret.
該死 閉上你的嘴 重來
Fucking... fucking stop.
你好
Okay. Hello.
Hello.
你好
瑪格麗特 是我布萊斯頓 我只是…
Margaret, it's Braxton. I was just...
天啊 你這蠢貨
God! Motherfucker.
你這個蠢貨 聽好了 干就完了
Motherfucker! Just fucking do it.
干就完了
Fucking do it.
你給我干就完了
You fucking do it.
像個娘們兒似的
You fucking pussy!
嗨 嗨 嗨 瑪格麗特
Hi. Hi. Hi, Margaret.
嘿 瑪格麗特 是我
Hey, Margaret, it's-it's-it's...
怎么回事
Fuck, man,
你到底在那里害怕些什么呀 哥們兒
what are you so fucking scared of, man?
我們到底在聊什么呢
What are we even talking about here?
我們在聊兩個星期
We're talking about two weeks.
也就是
That's
十四天
14...
（德國布勒蒂頂級巧克力）
十四天 瑪格麗特 這一生
14 days, Margaret, in the life...
在他的… 在他的…
in a... in a... in a... in a...
在他的一生之中
in his... in his life.
你知道他的名字嗎
Do you know what his name is?
他叫格雷格
It's Greg.
他是…
It's... it...
他是我的格雷格
It's my Greg.
他是…
He is mine.
他是我的
? Yeah...
他當然會和我一起睡覺 當然會啦
Of course he's gonna sleep with me. Of course.
你要奶瓶嗎
You want a bottle? I'll get a...
我會給他奶瓶
I'll give him a bottle.
我會給他奶瓶的
I'll... I'll give him a bottle.
奶瓶嘛
A bottle.
我會… 我會… 我會…
I-I can... I can... I can... I can con...
我會慢慢和他培養…
I can connect with-with...
來吧
Come on.
瑪格麗特 是我布萊斯頓
Margaret, it's Braxton.
又是你
對 又是我 被你發現了 瑪格麗特
Yeah. Me again. You, uh... You got me there, Margaret.
聽著 我呢
Listen, I, uh...
一直在想我們上次說的話
You know, I was thinking about our last conversation,
我都已經想好了
and I have gone ahead and, uh, decided
我打算這周四就順道過去把小狗接回來
that I'm going to swing on through and pick up the pup on Thursday.
對 不 八周斷奶期
Yeah, no, weaned at eight weeks.
不 你上次…
No, you made that...
你上次說得很清楚 瑪格麗特 不
You made that abundantly clear, Margaret.
是的 我知道這才過去六周 但是
No, and I-I'm fully aware it's only been six,
知道嗎 柯基是種非常聰明的小狗
but, you know, a corgi is an enormously smart dog,
瑪格麗特 它…
Margaret, and...
說得對 我只是…
Fair enough. I just...
想破頭也沒想通
Not sure that I'm able to wrap my head
你們說要讓小狗和狗媽媽培養感情
around the logic of building a bond between
到底是出于什么邏輯
a puppy and its mother
畢竟它們這輩子都不會再見了 對吧
when it's literally never gonna see the mother again. Right?
所以為什么不能把那寶貴的兩周用來
I mean, why not take that precious two weeks
讓小狗和它的主人培養感情呢
and build a bond between the owner and its pup
他們才是要共度一生的伙伴
when they're gonna spend the rest of their lives together?
說得對 所以… 所以… 所以…
Well, no, but that's-that's-that's...
這世上才會有奶瓶喂養這種東西的存在
that's where the-the bottle-feeding component comes in.
我做這行已經30年了 我從來沒有遇到過
像你這么不成熟 這么自私 這么不可理喻
好吧 上帝啊
Jesus.
好吧 沒必要…
All right. Yeah, you really...
你在吼我 瑪格麗特 好吧
You're yelling at me, Margaret. Yeah.
行吧
Okay.
好的
好 兩周…
Yeah, see...
兩周后見
see you in two weeks.
好的 非常好
Yep. Perfect.
再見
Bye-bye.
去死吧
Fuck you!
去死吧 瑪格麗特 你這個臭女人
Fuck you, Margaret, you fucking bitch!
說說你自己吧 比如
So tell me about you.
一般在不忙的時候你會忙些什么
What do you... what do you do when you're not doing whatever it is you do?
你有什么愛好嗎
You got any hobbies?
比如 做做烘焙或者
Like, um, I don't know, you bake or-or...
你釣魚嗎
you fish?
不釣嗎
No?
不釣魚嗎 不釣嗎
You don't fish? No?
喜歡看書嗎 又或者
You like to read? Maybe...
種花呢
You garden?
（德語）電影
Film.
看電影
Movies.
最喜歡哪部
Uh, you got a favorite?
（德語）《綠野仙蹤》
Zauberer von Oz.
《綠野仙蹤》
Wizard of Oz.
想聽聽《綠野仙蹤》的趣聞嗎
Want to hear a little Oz fun fact?
那只叫托托的小狗
The little dog, Toto,
它的真名叫特里 狗狗特里
its real name was Terry. Terry the dog.
拍這部片子時 狗狗特里一周能賺125美元
Terry the dog made 125 bucks a week on Oz.
知道小矮人賺多少嗎 演那些芒奇金人的
You know what the little people made who played the Munchkins?
50美元
50 bucks.
這是對正義的嘲諷還是什么意思
I mean, is that a travesty of justice or what?
有時候我會想到那些小矮人 知道嗎
Sometimes I like to think about those little people, you know.
試著站在他們的位置看問題
Put yourself in their shoes.
幾個小矮人肯定會坐在一起 看著特里說
Bet they sat around with their little people friends, looking at Terry.
“看這個混蛋” 對吧
"Hey, this motherfucker, you know,
“它的薪水居然是我們的兩倍
this guy's making twice as much as we are.
我都不記得它在電影里有唱過歌
I don't remember Terry doing any song-and-dance numbers.
或者跳過舞”
Do you?"
（格蘭迪 來電）
什么事
What do you want?
布萊斯頓 嗨 你好 是我
Braxton, hi. Hello. It's me,
克里斯 你哥哥
Chris, your brother.
我知道是你
I know it's you.
你從我語氣里聽不出我知道你是誰嗎
You can't tell from the tone of my voice that I know it's you?
好吧 你聽起來有點不爽
Oh, well, you sound hostile.
你有什么事
What do you want?
我需要你幫忙
I need your help.
算了吧 先掛了
Ah. Goodbye.
布萊斯頓
B-Braxton?
天哪 我真是服了 我真是服了 你就是個…
Fuck. Unbelievable. Unbelievable. You just...
大混蛋
Motherf...
我的老天爺
Jesus Christ.
搞什么啊 行吧
The fuck... All right.
好吧 還記得上一次我幫你的時候
Well, the last time that I did help you,
差點毀了我的職業生涯 還記得嗎
it nearly cost me my career. Are you aware of that?
你好像在生我的氣 為什么
You sound angry at me. Why?
對 你說對了 我很生氣
Yes, you're goddamn right I'm angry.
我生氣是因為年復一年都是我
I'm angry because, year after year, I call.
主動聯系的你 你從沒找過我
It's always me reaching out, and it's never you,
而現在 你莫名其妙打給我
and now, just out of the blue, you call.
為什么呢 就因為你需要我幫忙
And why? Because what, you... you need my help?
怎么 難道平時就不能打給我
How about... how about just calling?
隨便聊聊天嗎
How about just calling to shoot the shit?
嘿 兄弟 你好嗎 最近過得怎么樣
"Hey, man, how you doing? How have you been?"
圣誕快樂 生日快樂 小布 這很難嗎
"Merry Christmas. Happy birthday, B." What about that one?
可今天不是你生日 你生日是雙十一
But it's not your birthday. Your birthday's November 11th.
你個豬腦 我當然知道今天不是我生日
Ah, you dum-dum, I know it's not my fucking birthday.
這不是我的重點
That's not the fucking point of what I'm...
你想怎樣
What do you want?
你能在24小時內趕到洛杉磯嗎
Can you be in Los Angeles, California, in 24 hours?
布萊斯頓 喂
Braxton? Hello?
布萊斯頓
Braxton?
請別傷害我
Please don't hurt me.
抱歉 什么
I'm sorry. What?
請別 傷害我
Don't hurt me.
你怎么會這么說 我對你做什么了 我…
Why would you say that to me? What have I done to you? What...
我到底做什么了讓你覺得我會傷害你
Have I done anything at all that would give you the idea that I would do something to hurt you?
你怎么會突然冒出這么一句話呢
Why would you say that to me?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
是啊
Yeah.
我也很抱歉
That makes two of us.
我就想聊聊天而已
Trying to have a conversation.
你這姑娘真不會聊天
You kind of suck as a conversationalist.
我知道有語言障礙 但我的天哪
I mean, I know there's a language barrier, but holy shit,
我說的話不至于造成這么大的歧義吧
it's not like it's so fucking confusing what I'm saying to you.
（城市中心旅館）
我一直都找不到滿意的辦公椅
Can't seem to find an office chair I like.
那些椅子我實在是坐不慣
They're all so uncomfortable, you know?
其實真正的問題不在椅子
You know, actually, it's not the chair.
可能是因為你的那句“多虧你”
I think maybe it's what you said about putting me there.
我覺得我不配坐這個位子
I don't feel like I've earned the job.
你或許需要更好的腰部支撐
Maybe you need more lumbar support.
好市多有幾把椅子 腰部支撐做得很好
Costco has an excellent line of chairs that support the lower back.
當我沒說
Uh, never mind.
你兄弟知道案子的最新情況嗎
So, is your brother up to speed on the case?
他知道
Yes.
你們上次見面是什么時候
When was the last time you saw him?
八年前 在芝加哥
Eight years ago, in Chicago.
他是弟弟還是…
Younger brother or older?
我比布萊斯頓大兩歲
I'm two years older than Braxton.
他不太…
He doesn't...
有什么問題嗎
Is there something wrong?
他只是經常無緣無故生我的氣
He's just often very angry at me for no reason.
沒關系
It's fine.
我想他見到你一定很高興
Well, I'm sure he'll be happy to see you.
難說
Mm. Uh...
我明白 我也有兄弟姐妹
I-I get it. I have a sibling, too.
不然 你可以謝謝他來幫忙
Maybe thank him for coming to help.
告訴他你見到他有多高興
You know, tell him how glad you are to see him.
我的經驗是
It's just been my experience
人們都希望得到感謝 你懂的
that people want to be appreciated, you know?
他來了
That's him.
你好 布萊斯頓
Hello, Braxton.
這地方可真棒
This is pretty.
你是誰
Who are you?
我是瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜
I am Marybeth Medina,
金融犯罪執法局副局長
deputy director of Financial Crimes Enforcement.
聯邦政府的
A Fed?
你腦子抽風了嗎
You suffer a stroke?
你在生氣
You're upset.
我們一起合作 所以不管…
We're working together, so whatever...
你從事什么職業我目前都沒興趣
profession you're in, I currently have zero interest.
“目前”是吧
Currently, huh?
天啊 這下我放心了
Hey, gosh, that's great to hear.
單獨聊兩句好嗎
Talk to you for a second?
我們有日子沒見了 對吧
So it's been a minute, yeah?
-八年 零兩個月 -沒錯
- Eight years, uh, two months. - That's right.
你看起來不錯 克里斯
You look good, Chris.
我也這么想 我…
I think so, too. I...
布萊斯頓 謝謝你能來
Braxton, thank you for coming.
我真的很高興你來了
I'm really glad you're here.
她讓你這么說的
She tell you to say that?
對
Yeah.
好吧
去撒個尿
Got to squirt.
好吧 那個
Uh, just...
布萊斯頓 我們要不要再過一遍計劃
Braxton, should we go over the plan again?
-你要干什么 -能讓我安靜地撒泡尿嗎
What are you doing? Let me just take a piss, yeah?
好吧 然后我們再過遍計劃
Okay, and then we'll talk about the plan.
我是說 我們都看見了
我們都看見天空中的化學凝結尾跡了
就在昨天
你看到天上那道長長的尾跡了嗎
它延伸了好幾英里 千真萬確
懷疑論者說那只是飛機排放的冷凝物
-介意長相嗎 -無所謂
- Care what they look like? - Nah.
要幾個
How many?
一會兒就送過去
I'll send 'em up.
謝了
Appreciate it.
搞定
All righty.
你知道我的時間很值錢吧
My time's money, right?
是的 我知道
Yes, I've heard that.
我會寄發票給你的
I'll send you an invoice.
好的 很合理
Okay. Fair.
等拿到賬單再來和我說合理吧 大哥
See how fair you think it is when you get the bill there, hotshot.
沒關系 我肯定付得起
Oh, it's okay. I'm sure I can afford it.
“我肯定付得起”
"I'm sure I can afford it."
布萊斯頓
Braxton.
“布萊斯頓”
- "Braxton." - Braxton, don't repeat me.
布萊斯頓 別重復我的話
"Braxton, don't repeat me."
“布萊斯頓 別重復我的話”
- Braxton. - "Braxton."
布萊斯頓 你知道我不喜歡…
You know I don't like...
布萊斯頓 我好心和你說
Braxton, I'm asking you nicely.
-“布萊斯頓 我真的…” -布萊斯頓
- "Braxton, I really..." - Braxton.
好了 去那兒
All right, go...
去那邊站著 好嗎
just go stand over there, all right?
別嚇著人家
Don't be scary.
讓我來開口
Let me do the talking.
姑娘們
Ladies.
（西班牙語）你好 老爹
Hola, papi.
（西班牙語）你好
Hola.
隨便坐
Make yourself at home.
（西班牙語）你好
Hola, hola.
Hola.
你好
Hello.
-你一定就是那個狂野的吧 -不是
- You must be the wild one, huh? - Oh.
只要你們不亂動家具的位置 他就沒意見
Long as you don't rearrange the furniture, he's A-OK.
不如先把這個給了 好嗎 這是你的
Let's just, uh... Okay. Let's just get this over with now, yeah?
（西班牙語）謝謝
Gracias.
（西班牙語）我喜歡爽快的人
（西班牙語）謝謝 親愛的
（西班牙語）不客氣 應該的
De nada, de nada.
給你的
Here you go.
（西班牙語）謝謝Gracias.
謝謝 姑娘們
Thank you, ladies.
我和我朋友剛才在這兒聊天
You know, me and my friend here, we were, uh... we were just talking.
有件事或許你們能為我們解答
Just, maybe you could settle something for us.
如果你們走進這樣一個房間
Now, what happens, you walk into a room like this,
兩個男人坐在這兒 等著你們出現
two guys sitting here, all right, waiting for you--
如果出事了要怎么辦
what happens if things turn bad?
別緊張 不是說我們
Now, look, it's... it's not us.
我倆就像小綿羊一樣 好嗎
We're as tame as a tulip, okay?
我只是好奇 萬一有人想要動你們
I'm just wondering what happens if somebody puts their hands on you
讓你們不舒服
a way you don't like, if...
或者不讓你們離開
maybe we don't let you leave.
我想在這種情況下
I imagine there's somebody
你們一定會打電話求助吧
you call in a situation like that, right?
肯定有人負責這事 他會立刻出現
Somebody whose job it is to show up here,
確保你們大家沒事
make sure you guys are okay.
我就實話實說吧
Now, I want to be completely clear.
我對他的名字不感興趣 叫什么都無所謂
I'm not interested in names here. I could care less what his name is.
只是
Just...
我要怎么做 才能讓那個倒霉蛋
what would it take for me to get that certain somebody
立馬趕過來
to show up here?
（西班牙語）這家伙瘋了嗎
?Está loco este gringo?
（西班牙語）不知道 不太對勁
（西班牙語）他們顯然不是來上床的
（西班牙語）但他們不要情報 也不想知道名字嗎
托馬斯
Se llama Tomas.
（西班牙語）他叫托馬斯
His name is Tomas.
布萊斯頓你忘了嗎 托馬斯
Braxton, remember? Tomas.
（西班牙語）我們走吧 現在就走
-（西班牙語）不 等一下 沒準他們能… -（西班牙語）等什么
（西班牙語）幫什么 他剛才說了托馬斯的名字
什么
What? What?
（西班牙語）或許他們幫不了你 可誰知道呢
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
沒關系 沒關系
Shh, shh, shh, shh. It's okay. It's okay.
（西班牙語）幫什么 他們根本不認識我們
（西班牙語）除非他們當場殺了我們
（西班牙語）為什么不能聽他們說完呢
（西班牙語）別抱太大希望
（西班牙語）我們繼續跟著他 他會殺了我們的
（西班牙語）別傻了 想想華雷斯
Piensa en Juárez.
（西班牙語）華雷斯怎么了
?Qué pasa en Juárez?
華雷斯的事與你無關
Juárez is none of your business.
（西班牙語）我們走吧
Vámonos.
（西班牙語）不 我想看看他們會怎么做
（西班牙語）原諒我
（西班牙語）你真蠢
Eres una estúpida.
這是你的錢 拿著吧
That's your money. You take it.
（西班牙語）我們走
Vámonos.
謝謝姑娘們
Thank you, ladies.
這點錢太少了 如果要逃離那些人的話
It'll take a lot more than this to get away from those people.
好吧 也對
Okay. Okay.
來吧 “付得起”先生 給姑娘錢
Come on, Mr. "I Can Afford It." Pay the lady.
我是在冒死幫你們
I'm risking my life.
搞什么
Really?
給你
There we go.
現在可以了吧
托馬斯真的很壞
Tomas is real mean.
明白
Understood.
你們會教訓他吧
And you're gonna hurt him?
你想我們這么做嗎
Would you like us to?
是的
Please.
好的
Okay.
托馬斯
Tomas.
（西班牙語）我也不想打擾你 但事情有點嚴重
他們不放我們走
They won't let us leave.
（西班牙語）不 是真的 托馬斯 求你了
好的
Okay.
（西班牙語）謝謝
Gracias.
我們在235房間
I am in room 235.
好的
Okay.
像什么人
Uh, look like?
會計師
Accountants.
（西班牙語）會計師
好的 老板 再見
Okay, boss. Bye.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我沒有孩子
I don't have kids.
索基斯
Sorkis.
嘿 是我瑪莉貝絲 你那兒有消息嗎
Hey, it's Marybeth. What do you got for me?
交通監控錄像
Traffic cam footage.
（國土安全部 華盛頓特區）
我把畫面共享給你
Sharing my screens with you now.
只有兩個攝像頭拍到那個區域
Only two camera angles in that area.
金進了酒館
King enters...
在里面待了45分鐘
He's inside 45 minutes.
這時應該是聽到槍聲
Figure gunshots here.
人群四處逃散
Place stampedes.
沒有線索
Nothing.
誰都可能是槍手
Shooter could be anybody.
90秒后金也出來了
King exits 90 seconds later.
埃米利亞諾岡薩雷斯的電話打通了嗎
Um, any luck calling Emiliano Gonzalez,
雷的那個客戶
guy on Ray's client list?
伊迪絲的父親 通是通了 但…
Edith's father. Yes and no.
這里是岡薩雷斯家
Gonzalez residence.
埃米利亞諾岡薩雷斯在嗎
Is Emiliano Gonzalez there?
在 但也不在
Yes and no.
早在七年前岡薩雷斯先生就報警
Mr. Gonzalez had reported his daughter and young family missing
說他女兒和外孫失蹤了
seven years ago.
他出什么事了
Well, what happened to 'em?
販毒集團會綁架移民索取贖金
Cartels kidnap migrants for ransom
或賣給人販子
or for sale to traffickers.
如果勒索不成 也賣不掉呢
And if they can't ransom or sell?
那就是這個下場
You get this.
（面部識別 吉諾桑切斯）
吉諾桑切斯
Gino Sanchez.
我再打給你
I got to call you back.
聽說你扣了我的姑娘 混蛋
You got my fucking bitches, asshole.
準確來說 是混蛋們
Full disclosure: assholes.
-瑪麗拉 -進來聊嘛
Mariella!
-她在廁所里洗臉 -瑪麗拉
- She's just in the back getting freshened up. - Mariella!
進來吧 伙計 里面有無線 進來聊嘛
Hey, come on, man. We got Wi-Fi and everything.
（西班牙語）你在里面干什么 瑪麗拉
Come on in, no? Mariella!
我好像下手過重了
Guess I hit him harder than I thought.
他還活著
He's alive.
是的 我去拿東西
Yeah. Get my shit.
你們兩個是不是瘋了
Have you lost your fucking mind?
我們成綁架犯了嗎
What, are we kidnappers now?
綁架這個詞有點過了吧
Ah, kidnapping. That's pretty harsh, isn't it?
我們只是拘留了他
We merely, uh... We detained him.
為了審問
For questioning.
不 我們無權拘留任何人
Uh, no, we have no right to detain anyone.
這人可能知道是誰殺了雷金
This man may know who killed Ray King.
你不想知道嗎
Do you want to know what he knows or not?
如果警察攔下我
I-If the cops stop me,
如果他們要搜查后備箱怎么辦 大天才
if-if they search the trunk, what then, genius?
你好 夢中人
Hello, dreamboat.
能查到我位置嗎
Do you have my location?
是的
Yes.
我需要從這里到勝利大道一路綠燈
I need green lights from here to Victory Boulevard.
并報假警說這里以南十個街區
And please call in a fake robbery
發生搶劫案 轉移警方注意力
ten blocks south of here to distract the police
直到瑪莉貝絲安全回到民宿
until Marybeth gets safely home to the Airbnb.
-厲害 -還有嗎
- Damn. - Anything else?
查查雷金那天約了誰
I need to know who Ray King was meeting with.
可以了嗎
Okay?
相當可以好嘛
Pretty good, no?
走吧
Okay.
去吃點東西還是…
Go eat something or...
塔可鐘
Taco Bell.
那走吧
There we go.
（哈伯神經科學學院 賈絲廷）
早上好 孩子們
Good morning, boys and girls.
你們有沒有人想要暴力破解洛杉磯
Who wants to brute-force the city of Los Angeles?
（哈伯神經科學學院）
克里斯和他的朋友 今早將與我們遠程連線
We have Chris and his friend joining us remotely this morning.
他們希望我們找到并確認一名涉案人員
They would like us to find and identify a person of interest.
大家準備查看 所有道路和安防攝像頭的畫面
Let's prepare to examine all traffic and security cameras.
我一直在看國土安全部發來的監控
Okay, so I've been looking at the footage Homeland sent.
雷走進酒館 過了45分鐘后出來
Ray goes in, comes out 45 minutes later.
我們都不確定他是不是約了人見面
We don't even know for sure if he was there to meet anyone at all.
為什么不讓
Why don't we just, uh,
那個托馬斯告訴我們科布在哪里
get that Tomas guy to tell us where Cobb's at?
請問要怎么做到呢
And how are we gonna do that exactly?
你挖出他一只眼睛 然后給他看
If you just take out his eye, right, you show it to him?
告訴他你會把另一只也挖出來
And then you just say you're gonna take the other one out
除非他肯開口
unless he starts talking.
這招每次都奏效 屢試不爽
It works every time. It's, like, a ten out of ten.
沒人想做瞎子 對吧
Nobody wants to be blind, right?
給他看一只 他就知道你是認真的
You show 'em the one eye, they know you're serious.
安全鏈接已啟動
Secure link is active.
早上好
Good morning.
我已經給團隊介紹了情況
I've warmed up the orchestra.
我們正在尋找目標人物
We are looking for your person now.
正在搜索案發當天的監控錄像
Finding footage from the day of the incident.
調取街道攝像頭
Isolating street cameras.
聽著 我國土安全部的朋友
Look, my guy at Homeland,
他可是加州理工學院的計算機博士
he has a doctorate in computer science from Caltech.
隨便你的團隊在哪個數據庫里找
He can access every database you can name and some you can't.
那晚只有兩個監控拍到了
There were only two cameras recording that night.
我相信哈伯的孩子都很優秀
I'm sure the kids at Harbor are bright,
但這是在浪費時間
but we are wasting time.
你看
Oh, look.
這些是你在找的其他攝像頭
Here are the other cameras you were looking for,
麥迪娜副局長
Deputy Director Medina.
你現在可以解除靜音了
You can unmute your mic now.
所有人同步搜索
Everyone take a feed and look
那晚8點到10點之間的可疑線索
for anything suspicious between 8:00 and 10:00 p.m.
萊恩 仔細查看前門的畫面
Lane, let's see the front entrance,
槍響之后
post-gunfire.
艾登 后門發生了什么
Aidan, what's happening in the back?
尋找任何與當時情況不符的行為
Look for any behavior that doesn't match the situation.
倒回去 放大前門位置
Go back. Zoom in on the front door.
往后倒 那就是我們要找的對象
Reverse. That is our person of interest.
她不慌不忙
She's not hurrying.
也不害怕
She's not afraid.
讓我們趕在她來之前找到她
Let's find her before she arrived.
檢查每條小巷和街道
Check every alley and street.
覆蓋佛蒙特街和19街路口周圍四個街區
Cover four square blocks around Vermont and 19th.
她有意隱藏自己的臉 她知道哪里有監控
She's hiding her face. She knows where the cameras are.
（佛蒙特街）
邁爾斯 往后倒
Miles, reverse.
穿粉色夾克的人在自拍
Pink Jacket is taking a selfie.
讓我們獲取那張照片
Let's get that photo.
他們不可能從那個角度 放大她的手機屏幕
There's no way they can zoom in on her phone screen from that angle.
沒必要放大 他們會識別那女人的身份
They don't have to. They'll identify the woman
破解密碼 黑進她的手機
and find likely passwords, hack into the phone
然后用郵件發送過來
and email the selfie.
好吧 當然啦
Yeah, okay. Sure.
長嘆一口氣
Heavy sigh.
是不是該讓普通人見識一下 克里斯
Would you like to bring the normie up to speed, Chris?
我也這么想
That's what I would do.
進行面部掃描 確認身份
Run facial scan for I.D., please.
-我來 -我來
- I got it. - I got it.
克里斯 萊恩和查爾斯正在正面較量
Chris, Lane and Charles are going head-to-head for this one.
（駕照 帕梅拉里德）
你好 帕姆 讓我們互相認識一下吧
Hello, Pam. Let's get to know each other.
（愛荷華州得梅因市格蘭德大道12號）
愛荷華州 世界上第一臺電腦誕生的地方
Iowa. Birthplace of the world's first computer.
讓我們拜訪一下帕姆
Let's pay Pam's a visit.
艾登 那個郵編區域
Aidan, that zip code
歸屬中西部電力能源公司管轄
is serviced by Midwest Power and Energy.
從公用事業公司接入
They're entering from the utility company.
再跳轉至網絡中無防護的打印機
They'll jump to an unsecured printer on the network
或智能恒溫器
or a smart thermostat.
（恒溫器）
這些孩子是什么人
Who are these kids?
和我一樣的人
My people.
和我們一樣的人比你想象中更多
There are more of us than you think,
麥迪娜副局長
Deputy Director Medina.
斯凱 我們需要智能家居網絡的密碼
Skye, we need the password to the smart home network.
（輸入密碼）
（找到密碼）
（帕姆的筆記本電腦）
早上好 愛荷華
Good morning, Iowa.
早上好 帕姆
Good morning, Pam.
別讓帕姆舒服地坐下來
Let's not let Pam get comfortable.
這么做不對
This isn't right.
萊恩 讓她離開那把椅子
Lane, get her out of that chair
然后我們去找那張照片
and let's go find that photo.
（打印機）
（打印測試頁）
邁爾斯 她回來時把頁面調回去
Miles, have that page ready when she comes back.
查爾斯 趁現在進入她的相冊
Charles, get into her photo library.
我們不能這么做 讓她停下來
We-we can't do this. Tell her to stop.
克里斯 請向普通人解釋一下
Chris, please explain to the normie
我們需要有始有終
we need to finish what we've started.
紅燈
Red light.
艾登 輪到你了
Aidan, your turn.
（門鈴）
綠燈
Green light.
快讓她停下
Tell her to stop.
她來了 紅燈
Here she comes. Red light.
萊恩 讓鄰居聽到她的電視
Lane, let the neighbors hear that TV.
（廚房智能電視）
抹上黃油嗎
All in... all in the butter.
沒錯 把它們統統抹上黃油
Yeah, yeah. All that butter.
對 全部抹上 有多少抹多少
All right, all that butter, and then...
然后再加鹽
A little bit of salt.
沒錯
Mm-hmm.
說來好笑 自從搬來愛荷華之后就沒吃過
告訴她停下 馬上
Tell her to stop now.
克里斯 夠了 停下
Chris, enough. Stop.
告訴她停下
Tell her to stop.
快讓他們停下
Stop this now.
找到自拍了 艾登 發送電子郵件
Here's her selfie. Aidan, email photo.
（新建郵件）
-還是能嘗到甜味的 -沒錯
- You can actually taste the sweetness. - Yeah.
味道超好
Oh, I love that.
朋友 你這純屬愛荷華人的反應
That, my friend, is an Iowan response.
（發送）
斯凱 帶我們出去
Skye, get us out.
（停止運行）
而且他每天早上都會吃
He says he does it every morning.
-其實不錯 -你更喜歡生吃嗎
- It's so good. - You like the raw better?
我就喜歡生吃
I like the raw better.
你已經是純正的愛荷華人了
Proud of you. You are now a true Iowan.
邁爾斯 幫忙增強圖像
Miles, enhance, please.
運行國際刑警組織面部識別系統
Running Interpol facial recognition.
（美國國家安全局 墨西哥城 2023年10月）
（法國對外安全局 巴黎 2024年8月）
（國際刑警組織 羅馬 2022年9月）
（美國國家安全局 耶路撒冷 2024年4月）
（國際刑警組織 佛羅倫薩 2023年11月）
（英國軍情六處 莫斯科 2021年12月）
（美國中央情報局 布魯克林 2024年5月）
（身份查找）
（姓名未知）
看來她是最后一個和雷說話的人
It looks like she was the last person to speak to Ray,
但她不想被人發現
but she doesn't want to be found.
再見 夢中人
Goodbye, dreamboat.
（蒙特利爾）
（莫斯科）
雷為什么找這么一個殺人不眨眼的女人
Why would Ray meet with someone who killed all these people
去找那對母子
to find a mother and child?
那些人也不全是她殺的
She didn't kill all those people.
我是說起碼她沒殺那個人
I'm just saying, she definitely didn't kill that one or...
還有這個人 所以…
that one right there, so...
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
我只是隨便說說而已 你懂的
Eh... just kind of throwing it out there, that's all, you know.
只是種直覺
Just a hunch.
有根據的猜測
Educated guess.
真的 就是直覺
That's all it is, really.
他不可能知道這些
He has no way of knowing.
沒錯 我只是…
Yeah, I'm just...
-簡單地假設 -對
- It's hypothetical. - True.
-別再說了 -好的
- Stop talking. - Okay.
-不管怎樣 -我受夠了
- Regardless... - Oh, fuck no.
我
I...
你經常沒事承認自己殺人嗎
Do you... do you often confess to capital murder?
我其實什么都沒說 你仔細想想
I actually didn't say anything, if you think about it.
我只是指了指照片
I literally made a gesture.
這大概讓她不爽了
I guess that bothered her.
再見 就這樣 我退出
Goodbye. That's it. I'm out.
好吧 等等 瑪莉貝絲
Okay. One moment, Marybeth, please,
占用你點時間 有件事你得想一下
for your time. One thing that you may want to consider
墻上掛著的那些照片里的人
is some of those men whose pictures were on the wall
不管他們是否被殺
may have... may not have been killed,
都很可能不是什么好人
were likely very unsavory characters...
他們是不是好人根本就不重要
It doesn't fucking matter if they're unsavory!
我們無權決定別人的生死
We don't get to decide who lives and who dies.
-顯然我有 -布萊斯頓
- Apparently, I do. - Braxton.
法律存在的意義 就是為了讓我們遠離那種人
The law is what separates us from people like him.
這真是我的榮幸
Been a pleasure and an honor.
希望下次能再次合作
Uh, hope we get to work with each other again.
多保重 注意安全
Uh, you take care and stay safe.
（西班牙語）打開該死的后備箱
該死
Fuck.
（西班牙語）快打開 混蛋
（西班牙語）放我出去 快停下
我們還有個麻煩
We have a problem.
-是后備箱里的人嗎 -沒錯
- Is it the man in the trunk? - It is.
聽起來是你的麻煩
Sounds like you got a problem.
拜托把他弄走
Remove him, please.
然后怎么處置他
And-and do what with him?
我會去找州總檢察長
I'm going to the state's attorney general.
真幸運這不是我的車
Sure am glad it's not my car.
知道嗎 我打給你就是個錯誤
You know what, I made a mistake calling you.
我會按我自己的方式來
Okay? I'm gonna do this myself,
照章辦事 不再撒謊 不再觸犯法律
by the book, no more lying, no more breaking the law.
告訴英國女 別再給我線索了
Tell the Brit no more tips.
在我回來前趕緊消失
And don't be here when I get back.
再讓我看見你們倆任何一個
If I see either of you again, I'll have you arrested.
我就逮捕你們
（墨西哥 華雷斯）
古蒂埃雷茲小姐 我不太明白
Ms. Gutierrez, I'm confused.
我的當事人唯一的過錯就是
The only thing that my client is guilty of
幫助了一位身陷困境的年輕女性
is coming to the aid of a young lady in distress,
在那之后 他被襲擊 毆打 還被綁架了
after which he was attacked, beaten and kidnapped.
但你們非但沒去追捕那兩個人
But instead of pursuing these men,
反而拿這個名叫科布的先生 來威脅我的當事人
you hold this Cobb individual over my client's head,
試圖用人口販賣的罪名指控他 并拿牢獄之災來威脅他
threatened him with prison time amidst accusations of human trafficking?
你們覺得我們的法律得多荒謬
In what bizarro legal world
才會讓大陪審團同意起訴我的當事人
do you imagine getting a grand jury indictment?
有意思
Funny.
我在向蘇迪奧提出同樣的認罪協議時
Exactly what Ike Sudio's lawyer said
他的律師也是這么說的
when I offered the same plea deal to his client.
我不認識什么蘇迪奧先生
I do not know Mr. Sudio.
但你的當事人好像認識
Looks like your client does.
你們可能沒有注意到
Now, what you don't see are
比如蘇迪奧舌頭上的咬痕和那只老鼠
the bite marks on Sudio's tongue and the rat.
老鼠跑進他嘴里時雙方都還活著
It went into his mouth when both were still alive.
好吧 我的直覺告訴我
Now-- and this is just a hunch--
艾克的位置肯定要比皮條客重要
I'm guessing Ike was more important than a pimp.
所以他們會怎么對你
What do you think they'll do to you?
行了 該說的都說了
Okay, we're done here.
最后提醒一句 蘇迪奧先生的律師失蹤了
I should note Mr. Sudio's attorney is missing.
是嗎
簽不簽
In or out?
負責洗錢的是艾克 伙計
Ike washed the fucking money, man.
人口販賣賺來的錢嗎
Money made from human trafficking?
大部分來自中美洲 墨西哥
Most are from Central America, Mexico.
跟毒品一樣 但更有賺頭
Like drugs, only better.
姿色好的能賺上五六年的錢
A good earner lasts five, six years.
大部分是女人
Mostly women--
賣去做妓女 下地種田 刷馬桶
on their backs, in the fields, scrubbing toilets.
而一些男人會去摘甜瓜 去屠宰場做苦力
Some men-- picking melons, slaughterhouse kill floors.
全是那些美國人不愿意干
Any job an American won't fucking do
機器也干不了的活兒
and a machine can't.
認識他嗎
Recognize him?
不認識
No.
這是八年前拍的
This was taken eight years ago.
我記得
Oh, yeah.
這女的能把男人榨干
Bitch would work a good man to death.
她接過幾次客 但跟個啞巴似的
She threw down a few times, but she was too quiet,
所以去干女傭的活兒了
so... did maid work mainly.
她叫伊迪絲 她在哪兒
Her name is Edith. Where is she?
她在阿瓦拉多街的停車場外 攔腰撞上了一輛車
She T-boned a car outside a parking garage on Alvarado
大概是四五年前的事了
four, five years ago.
所以她死了
So she's dead?
沒有 但聽說她從擋風玻璃飛了出去
No. Heard she went through the windshield, though.
對我們來說就算殘次品了
Too secondhand for us.
送去哪家醫院了
What hospital?
我怎么知道
Fuck would I know?
她父親在得克薩斯 為什么她不去找他
She had a father in Texas. Why wouldn't she go to him for help?
你問他啊
Ask him.
現在在問你
We're asking you.
你如果如實交代一切 作為交換
You put everything on the record, you get immunity in exchange
你就能得到豁免
for your testimony.
最后的機會
Last chance.
把該死的筆給我
Give me the fucking pen.
見鬼
Fuck!
快趴下
Get down!
過去5年里 那個停車場有18起事故報告
18 reported accidents within the garage in the last five years.
都不嚴重 沒那么嚴重的
None serious, none on that level.
停車場出口在哪條街上
What street did the garage exit out to?
阿瓦拉多街 一英里半徑內有32起事故
Alvarado. 32 accidents within a mile radius,
3起涉及嚴重人身傷害
three with serious bodily injuries.
有涉及從那個停車場出來的車嗎
Did any of those involve a vehicle exiting a garage?
1起
One.
傷亡情況
Injuries?
1人 傷勢嚴重
One, critical.
一個身份不明的女人 獨自駕車
An unidentified woman, sole occupant.
哪家醫院
Hospital?
大學醫學中心
University Medical Center.
什么車
Vehicle?
豐田凱美瑞
Toyota Camry.
顏色
Color?
藍色
Blue.
查找醫學中心的病人檔案 謝謝
Explore the medical center's patient files.
Thank you.
“我沒有孩子”
"I don't have kids."
謝天謝地
Thank God for that.
什么
What?
什么什么
旅館那女人說的 “我沒有孩子”
The woman at the hotel, she said, "I don't have kids."
對 我記得
Yeah, I remember, man.
別再想這事兒了
You got to let it go already.
我是說為什么這么重要
Well, I'm saying, why is that significant?
為什么做母親很重要
Why is being a mother important?
好吧 兄弟
You know, man,
很遺憾地告訴你 關于母愛的重要性
I don't think you and I are really authorities on the importance of motherly love,
你和我都沒有資格發言
I hate to tell you.
這就是你的生活
This is it, huh?
住在鐵皮飯盒里
Live in a lunch box.
挺舒服的
It's quite comfortable.
四季酒店也很舒服 住大房子也行
Well, so is the Four Seasons. Or a house.
跟老爸一樣摳門 比葛朗臺還葛朗臺
Cheap like Pop. Tighter than bark on a tree, aren't you?
不 他不是摳門 他是節儉
No, he wasn't cheap. He was frugal.
-那叫節儉 -是的
- He was frugal? - Yes.
瞎扯淡
Bullshit.
“七件襯衫 七條內褲和七雙襪子
"Seven T-shirts, seven pairs of underwear and socks
我只需要這些”
is all I need."
一個大老爺們兒戴塊天美時 太可悲了
Fucking grown man wearing a Timex, dude. He was fucking pathetic.
看看這個
Look at that.
-看到沒 -看到了
- See that? - Yes.
這比他一年賺的還多
It's worth more than he made in a year.
你覺得他會怎么說
What do you think he'd say about this?
他會說顯示的時間不都一樣嗎
He would say it's the same time on his watch.
他可能真會這么說
He probably would, wouldn't he?
你開心嗎 布萊斯頓
Are you happy, Braxton?
我開心嗎
Am I happy?
是的
Yes.
當然
Yeah.
老兄 我當然開心啦 我為什么會不開心呢
Yeah, man, of course I'm happy. Why wouldn't I be happy?
你是這個世界的過客 沒有另一半
You're a transient. You have no significant other.
始終孤身一人 沒有朋友 也沒有…
You're completely alone, no friends or...
什么都沒
nothing, you have no...
你在說我還是在說你
We talking about me or we talking about you?
你想過我為什么會孤身一人嗎 克里斯
You ever thought about why I'm alone, Chris?
因為你很粗魯 很自私 還有…
'Cause you're abrasive or selfish or...
你經常說臟話
well, you swear too often.
大哥 我一個人是因為我想一個人
Dude, I'm alone because I... I want to be alone.
我選擇一個人
I choose to be alone.
這樣我就不需要向任何人交代 懂嗎
I don't have anybody that I got to answer to, you know,
不用向人報備
check in with.
我環游世界 住遍各大五星級酒店
I-I travel the world. I stay at five-star hotels.
想做什么做什么
I do what I want when I want it.
我還有槍 想去哪里去哪里
Have gun, will travel, motherfucker.
所以當然啦 開心得不得了 簡直爽爆了
I mean, yeah. Shit yeah, I'm happy.
你就放一百個心吧
I'm fucking happy. Bet your ass I'm happy.
我挺想有個能報備的人
I'd like to have someone to check in on.
-是嗎 -是的
- Yeah? - Yes.
那就養條狗吧
Well, get a dog.
你有狗嗎
Do you have a dog?
我很快就有了
I'm getting a dog.
給你看看
Look at this.
你看
Yeah.
它叫格雷格
That's Greg.
有點牽強
Unconvincing.
什么叫有點牽強 它叫格雷格
What do you mean "unconvincing"?
他馬上就是我的了
That's Greg. I'm getting this dog.
不 你只是喜歡養狗這主意
Well, you like the idea of a dog.
所有養狗的人都是因為喜歡養狗這主意
Anybody who has a dog likes the idea of getting a dog.
所以他們才會去養狗
It's why they got the dog in the first place.
-你有固定的住所嗎 -沒有
- Do you have a permanent residence? - No.
-長期不在家時有人照顧你的狗嗎 -也沒有
- Anyone to care for your dog during long absences? - I do not.
-你生活規律嗎 -不
- Do you keep a regular schedule
-按時吃飯和睡覺嗎 -怎么可能
- in terms of eating, sleeping? - No, I don't.
你適合養貓
You're a cat person.
這沒什么不好的
There's nothing wrong with that.
說的也是 要是養只貓 至少貓會想我
Well, you know something, if I had a cat, at least the cat would miss me.
不好說
Doubtful.
可能吧
Possible.
不可能
Nah.
克里斯 到底是因為你還是因為我
Chris, is it because of you or because of me?
什么
What?
你一直…
That you, like...
-什么 -你…
- What? - You...
-我沒聽懂 -你不會…
- I don't understand. - You don't...
你好像就是
You just, like,
從來
don't, like...
不會想我
like, miss me.
問題在你還是在我
Like, is that 'cause of you or me?
我曾經找了你很多年
I spent years looking for you.
我只想知道你在哪兒 而你從沒找過我
I was just trying to track you down, but you don't look for me at all.
然后我終于找到你了
And then I finally find you,
然后
and I...
當時還是我救了你一命
you know, I was there, I saved your life.
然后你說你會來找我的 你說…
And you said that you would come and find me. You said...
你很快就會來找我 然后你又消失了
you would come and find me soon, and then you just disappeared again,
不是嗎
I guess.
你有我的電話號碼
You had my phone number.
其實我想問你的是
I guess what I'm asking you, man, is, like...
你不想我是因為我的問題還是…
Do you not miss me because of me, or is it...
-因為你有… -我有什么
- ...is it 'cause of your, like... - My what?
你懂的 就是你的狀況
You know, your... your condition.
我就這樣
I'm just me.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在給下肢涂防曬霜
I am applying sunscreen to my lower extremities.
這是防曬指數100的防曬霜
This is 100 SPF.
我小時候曾經不止四次被曬傷
I had more than four sunburns in my childhood,
所以 像我們這種人患黑色素瘤的幾率
so we're more than twice as likely to develop melanoma as adults.
是別人的兩倍多
- I take precautions. - Can I get a little bit?
-能給我也來點嗎 謝謝 -當然啦
- Yeah, sure. - Can I get some? Thanks, man.
你知道我不喜歡這樣
You know I don't like that.
這不好玩 布萊斯頓 我喜歡…
That's not funny, Braxton. I like thing...
太有意思了
Oh, it's so funny.
-有時我真想揍你一拳 -真是太有意思了
- I want to sock your mouth sometimes. - It's so funny.
你猜我在想什么
You know what I think?
我覺得我們應該大醉一場
I think we got to go get drunk.
走吧 伙計
Come on, man.
我們去喝個痛快
Let's go get drunk.
好吧
Okay.
（牛仔宮殿酒吧）
（歌詞大意）兒子 你肯定會成功
? Son, you finally got it made ?
老漢克成功了
? Old Hank made it here
我們都相信你也會
and we're all sure that you will ?
但我不認為漢克是這樣做的
? but I don't think Hank done it this way ?
? I don't think old Hank done it this way...
這里好像跟我想的不太一樣
I don't know if it's, uh, exactly what I had in mind, you know?
我是說 這可是洛杉磯
I mean, it's... it's L.A.
對我來說應該是夜店 泊車小哥
To me, that means nightclubs,
天鵝絨繩子 滿地都是人渣
valets, velvet ropes, douchebags everywhere.
不是這種土里土氣的小鎮 懂嗎
Not really a honky-tonk type town, you know?
怎么說呢 我沒想到你會喜歡
I don't know, I just never took you for, like,
西部鄉村風 不過
a country-western kind of guy, but
挺好的 我是說
it's cool. I mean,
你既然能裝成普通的會計師
I guess you pretend to be an ordinary accountant,
那今晚你也能裝成個牛仔 對吧
you can, uh, pretend to be a cowboy tonight, right?
不 對 好吧
No. Yes. Okay.
什么叫“不 對 好吧”
What do you mean "no, yes, okay"?
我們倆是在聊天嗎 克里斯
Are we having a conversation here, Chris?
對了 說到牛仔 我的感覺是
By the way, as far as the whole cowboy thing,
阿甘鞋呢 還是差了點意思 不過…
I think the Forrest Gump shoes, they're a bit of a misfire, but...
那個…
Well...
那個什么 什么
"Well" what? What?
你們好
Hey, now.
你好
Hello.
樂隊可以點歌
Band's looking for requests.
你有喜歡的歌嗎 帥哥
Is there a song you like, handsome?
我覺得艾倫杰克遜挺好 類似于那種的
I guess I'm good with, like, Alan Jackson, something like that.
告訴他 隨便哪首都行 親愛的
Tell 'em that'll, uh... that'll do me just fine, sweetheart.
好吧 別這么急 動感夜貓
Okay, slow down, Night Moves.
我是在問他
I was, uh, asking him.
我叫安吉
I'm Angie.
你好安吉 我叫克里斯
Hello, Angie. My name is Chris.
你最喜歡什么 克里斯
What's your favorite tune, Chris?
我最喜歡科普蘭的《阿巴拉契亞之春》
My favorite song is "Appalachian Spring" by Copland.
第二喜歡呢
Second favorite.
在這種場合的話
Uh... in this context, yes.
金屬樂隊的《睡魔入侵》
Metallica, "Enter Sandman."
這恐怕超出了他們的專業范疇
I don't think that's in their wheelhouse.
好吧
Ah, yeah.
也許你該問一個更了解樂隊業務能力的人
Maybe you should ask someone more familiar with the band's capabilities.
好吧
Okay.
-不對 -我…
- No. - I...
-不對 -什么
- No. - What?
你在干嗎 就差一口氣 你怎么…
What are you do... You were right there. Why'd you...
-你怎么就一落千丈了 -那我該說什么
- why'd you go down like that? - What was I supposed to say?
聊得好好的 眼看就成了
You were going up. It was working.
什么叫“我該說什么”
What were you supposed to say?
你就說“你選吧”不就行了
Just say, "You pick," you know?
但她問的是我最喜歡的歌
But she asked me what my favorite song was.
-老兄 她不是在問你問題 -不 她問了
- Dude, she wasn't asking you... - Yes, she did. She asked me.
-她過來是因為她喜歡你 -她讓我選
- Because she liked you. - She lit...
對此我跟你一樣震驚 但她喜歡你
I-I'm just as shocked as you are, but she liked you.
所以她才走過來
That's why she came here.
你可以理解為求偶
I don't know, it was like a mating call.
真不懂你怎么會看不出來呢
I mean, how do you not see... It doesn't...
我的大腦不是那樣運作的 布萊斯頓
My brain doesn't work that way, Braxton.
你聽我說 嘿
Look, dude, I... Hey,
嘿 嘿 嘿
hey, hey, hey.
挺好的
It was good.
聽到沒 挺好的
You hear me? It was good.
我是說 你對她有意思 她對你也有意思
But, I mean, it seemed like you were seeing it, and she was seeing it.
-是的 -但就是…
- Yes. - It was just...
你讓她笑了
you made her smile.
我不知道你說的第一個是什么
I mean, I don't know what the-the first thing you said,
但金屬樂隊那個真的太搞笑了
but the Metallica thing, that... it was funny.
沒準她覺得你的回答很可愛
You know, it could've been perceived as, I-I don't know, like, cute or something like that,
但你絕對讓她笑了
but it definitely made her smile.
我是說 也許是你少了點自信
I think maybe you don't give yourself enough credit.
你只是有點…
You're just, like, sort of...
你要做什么 伙計
What are you gonna do, man?
去尿尿嗎 你去哪兒
You... going to piss? Where are you going?
（歌詞大意）他每年只來鎮上兩次
? He only came to town about twice a year ?
他會買一百磅酵母和一些銅線
? He'd buy a hundred pounds of yeast and some copper line ?
大家都知道他釀私酒
? Everybody knew that he made moonshine...
不 不 不 不是吧
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
帶上他的全部家當走進山谷
? Headed up the holler with everything he had ?
那是我出生前的事 但有人告訴我
? Before my time, but I've been told ?
他再也沒有從銅頭蛇路回來
? he never come back from Copperhead Road...
你可以的 準備好了
You got it. Ready?
就是這樣
There you go.
嘿
Hey.
開什么國際玩笑
Get the fuck out of...
現在爸爸開著大引擎道奇賣威士忌
? Now, Daddy ran the whiskey in a big-block Dodge ?
嘿
那是從梅森旅館拍賣會上買的
? Bought it at an auction at the Masons' lodge ?
一側車門寫著“約翰遜縣治安官”
? "Johnson County Sheriff" painted on the side ?
他噴了一層油漆 又看了看里面
? He just shot a coat of primer, then he looked inside ?
他和叔叔拆掉了引擎
? Well, him and my uncle shut that engine down ?
但我還記得那隆隆聲
? Well, I still remember that rumblin' sound... ?
嘿
Hey!
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
警長半夜過來了
? The sheriff came around in the middle of the night ?
聽到媽媽哭了 知道事情不對勁
? Heard Mama cryin', knew somethin' wasn't right ?
他帶著每周的貨去諾克斯維爾
? He headed down to Knoxville with the weekly load ?
你能聞到銅頭蛇路上燃燒的威士忌味
? You could smell the whiskey burnin' down Copperhead Road... ?
跳起來
Let's go!
踢 踢
Kick!
嘿 看到沒有 那是我哥
Hey, you see that? That's my brother.
臺上那個是我大哥
That's my big brother up there.
銅頭蛇路
? Copperhead Road ?
天啊 真對不起
Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
跳得好
抱歉 我不是故意的
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
-謝謝 -你跳得很好
- Thank you. - So he dances.
好吧
Well...
還真是讓人大跌眼鏡
Well, I'll be dipped in dog shit.
你好
Oh, hello.
跳得還真像回事
That was some dancing.
挺靈活的嘛 大塊頭
Light on your feet, big man.
謝謝 我是個新手 這是我第一次 所以…
Thank you. Yes. I'm a beginner. It's my first time, so...
我不是在夸你 傻大個
It wasn't a compliment, hoss.
杰瑞 你別這樣
Jerry. Don't start.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
-往前看 小子 -這可不太友好
- Eyes forward, son. - Whoa. Well, that's not kind.
我覺得你沒在聽我說話
Hey, I don't think you heard me.
-跟你說話的時候眼睛看著我 -嘿
Look at me when I'm fucking talking to you.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 行了
Hey, come on.
這里是牛仔的地盤
You're in cowboy country.
看出來了
Oh, I see.
在我們這兒 不允許招惹別人的女朋友
We don't mess with another man's girl down here.
你來自格倫代爾 杰瑞
You're from Glendale, Gerald,
而我也不是你女朋友
and I'm not your girl.
沒關系 我弟弟今晚還沒盡興 現在好了
It's okay. My brother wasn't having a good time tonight, but now he will.
好了 打我 杰瑞
Okay, hit me, Jerry.
-我會連你弟弟一起收拾 -那正好
- Well, your brother can get it, too. - Oh, good.
你的臉就像屁股
Your face is like an anus.
有本事就打我 哦 糟了
Swing at me, Jerry! Oh, no.
卡其褲朋友想跟我打架
Khaki Pants here wants to scrap.
-杰瑞 -這下可慘了
- Jerry. - Oh, goodness gracious.
那就揍他
Fucking hit him.
-嘿 幫我拿著 -讓他見識一下
- Hey. Show him what you got, Jerry. - Here, hold this.
揍扁他 杰瑞
Get him, Jerry.
-拿出拳頭來 混蛋 -我準備好了
- Knuckle up, motherfucker. - I'm prepared.
-伙計們 停下 -拿出拳頭來 混蛋
- Guys, stop. - Knuckle up, motherfucker.
-你看上去很兇 來啊 杰瑞 -住手 杰瑞
Hey. Stop. Jerry.
-來打我呀 -揍他 杰瑞
- Oh, come on now. - Go, Jerry!
爽爆了
Goddamn!
你說這世上還有什么比收拾一個
Is there anything in this world better than punching
欠收拾的混蛋更開心的事嗎
a motherfucker in the face who's got it coming? Huh?
-這個嘛… -什么
- Well... - Huh? What?
（安吉 電話號碼）
-假的吧 -真的
- No. - Yes.
鐵樹開花啊
Shut the front door.
好你啊
You! Hey!
嘿
Yes. Ha!
Hey!
-我會著呢 -你這家伙
- I'm very smooth. - You!
看看你
You, look at you!
抱歉 您說您是…
I'm sorry, it was, uh, Miss...
（加利福尼亞州 博伊爾高地 大學醫學中心）
麥迪娜副局長
Deputy Director Medina.
有法院傳票才能查看病人檔案
Yeah, well, patient files past and present require a subpoena.
這點你肯定知道 麥迪娜小姐
I'm quite sure you know that, Miss Medina.
是的 我知道
Yes, I do.
八年前一個女人和她的孩子失蹤了
A woman and her child disappeared eight years ago.
現在他們要么死了 要么生不如死
Now they're either dead or living a nightmare.
聽著 你能不能通融一下
Look, could you just do this for me, please?
我真的需要你的幫助 我會非常感激
I really need your help, and I just... I...
我得收到法院的指令才行
Yeah, and I need a court order to do so.
抱歉 請留步
Now, I'm sorry.
嘿
Hey.
哈伯神經科學學院
Harbor Neuroscience.
傳說中的那個哈伯嗎
The Harbor Neuroscience?
財政部和哈伯已經開展合作
Treasury and Harbor have partnered to support
會大力支持研究特殊能力者的
health care professionals who work with individuals
專業醫療人員
possessing unique abilities.
怎么個支持法
Define "support."
找到了
Here we go.
無名氏 636號
Jane Doe 636.
五年前入院 頭骨骨折
Five years ago.
下巴 肋骨 左臂骨折
Skull fracture, jaw, ribs, left arm broken.
以及因為車禍導致的面部大面積損傷
And extensive facial injuries as a result of an auto accident.
（西班牙語）怎么受傷的
（西班牙語）我被人襲擊了
神志不清
Delirious,
送來時 時有意識 時而沒有
in and out of consciousness when she arrived.
說自己是被某個人襲擊了
Said something about being attacked by somebody.
（觀察第1天）
在進行重建手術之前
Prior to reconstructive surgery,
她接受了我設計的神經康復治療方案
she was exposed to neuro-rehabilitation strategies
是針對腦部嚴重受創的患者
I designed to treat individuals with extensive brain trauma.
有多嚴重
How extensive?
幾乎完全喪失記憶
A nearly total loss of memory.
（觀察第4天）
我在大學是象棋高手
I played top boards in college.
就算她會下也不記得怎么下了
If Jane ever played, she didn't remember how.
這是三天后
That's three days later?
后天學者癥候群
Acquired savant syndrome.
很罕見 所以有些專家對此表示懷疑
So rare some neurologists doubt it exists.
但你沒有
But you don't?
在極其罕見的情況下
Victims of blunt force trauma
鈍器創傷的受害者
can, on extremely rare occasions,
會開發出令人驚嘆的能力
exhibit extraordinary outcomes.
一個從沒彈過鋼琴的女人 不幸摔裂了頭骨
A woman who's never played piano fractures her skull in a fall,
一天內竟彈起了拉赫曼尼諾夫
masters Rachmaninoff in a day.
一個棒球迷被時速90英里的棒球擊中頭部
A baseball fan takes a 90-mile-per-hour foul ball
醒來后發現僅一個下午
to the head and wakes to discover
他就學會了一門外語
he can learn a foreign language in an afternoon.
這怎么可能
How is that possible?
他們的大腦
Their brains,
要怎么說呢 就像是被重連了
for lack of a better word, are rewired,
解鎖了隱藏的能力
unlocking hidden abilities,
理論上這些能力其實我們都有
abilities that, at least theoretically, we all possess.
而她的天賦則是象棋
And Jane's talent was chess?
不是
No.
不完全是
Not exactly.
（觀察第11天）
她遭受的腦損傷 激活了她的額葉和頂葉皮質
The brain injury Jane suffered lit up her frontal and parietal cortex.
將軍
Checkmate.
那些區域主要負責模式識別
Those areas responsible for pattern recognition, problem solving,
解決問題 批判性思維
critical thinking.
象棋高手們依賴的也是這些區域
The same areas of the brain chess masters rely on.
（觀察第23天）
區別在于 象棋高手的這些能力只涉及象棋
Caveat is their abilities start and stop with chess.
但在她身上則不一樣
In Jane Doe, they didn't.
后天學者癥候群可以解釋
Acquired savant syndrome
她呈指數增長的解碼能力
would explain the exponential acceleration of her ability
吸收信息的能力
to decode and assimilate information,
以及手眼協調能力 但是
the hand-eye coordination,
無法解釋的是 為什么她會失去記憶
but what it doesn't explain is why her memory was all but erased.
以及性格的改變
Or the personality change.
我的猜測是
My theory?
創傷不僅重連了她的大腦
The trauma that rewired her brain
同時也切斷了所有沒必要的神經網絡
also unplugged any unnecessary neural networks.
對于什么而言沒必要
Unnecessary for...?
對于生存
Survival.
大腦的額葉也是我們做出 “戰斗或逃跑”決策的區域
The brain's frontal lobes are also where our fight-or-flight decisions are made.
（觀察第62天）
我認為象棋對她的吸引力并不是策略
I think the appeal of chess wasn't strategy...
而是戰斗
...but combat.
我不知道意外前她的生活是怎樣的
I don't know what Jane's life was like prior to the accident,
但不管她入院時是什么樣
but whoever she was when they brought her in...
（觀察第62天）
她離開時已經完全不同了
...wasn't the same person who left.
在接下來的幾個月里 她變得…
Over the following months, she became
（觀察第105天）
越來越孤立 具有攻擊性
increasingly isolated. Aggressive.
直到有一晚
Until one night,
她把一名值班保安打暈了
she beat a security guard unconscious,
拿走了他的槍
took his gun...
從此消失了
...and disappeared.
你說她幾乎失去了所有記憶
Y-You said her memory was all but erased.
那后來她有想起任何事故前的事情嗎
D-Did she retain any memory of her life before the accident?
家人 孩子 任何事
Family, kids, anything?
對 這個問題我也問過她很多遍
Yeah, I asked her that exact question multiple times.
只有一次 她好像想起了什么
Only once did she come up with something.
那回到家人的問題
Let's go back over family.
你有任何關于孩子 或者丈夫的記憶嗎
Um, any memory of children or a husband?
《黃鼠狼跑了》
"Pop! Goes the Weasel"?
不如 我們訂個晚餐
So, should we order in some dinner?
討論下經費補助 下一步怎么操作
Discuss the grant? Next steps?
申請表就在我車上
Uh, the applications are in my car.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
連這個女人 是不是在我手底下工作都不知道
You're asking me to divulge the identity of a woman
你就要我透露她的身份給你
who may or may not be under my employment.
我知道她在為我們賣命 巴圖
I know she works for us, Batu.
那么 你是怎么知道的
And, uh, you know this how?
我拒掉的那一半工作
Half those jobs I turned down...
我只是
I just...
想和她談談 僅此而已
I just want to talk to her. That's all.
和她談談
Talk to her?
為什么
Why?
是家事
It's-it's a family thing.
不用告訴我
Don't tell me.
要不是因為某些很麻煩的原因
The one man I'd terminate
我愿意不收錢干掉那個家伙
for free minus one very inconvenient fact.
我知道 因為他是我哥
I know. He's my brother.
不是
No.
是因為我怕他殺光我的殺手
He might kill all my killers.
沒錯
我要睡了
I'm going to bed.
布萊斯頓
Braxton,
告訴我那個殺人機器現在不在你的身邊
tell me that engine of destruction isn't with you now.
是的 先生 他不在
No, sir, he is not.
因為上次你處理家事的時候 差點毀了我
Because the last time you had a family thing, it nearly ruined me.
彼此彼此
Makes two of us.
-既然你在洛杉磯 -怎么了
- Since you're in Los Angeles... - Yeah?
我們有一個新客戶
We have a new client
他自家的殺手搞不定一個活兒
whose in-house hitter isn't getting the job done.
我先把照片發給你
Sending a photo now.
等我們談成后 再給你具體指示
Instructions to follow only if we engage.
（瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜）
如果我需要你幫忙
I will let you know soon
我會盡快聯系你的
if I need your services.
（西班牙語）“想想華雷斯”
"Piensa en Juárez."
華雷斯 為什么是華雷斯
Juárez. Why Juárez?
“我沒有孩子
"I don't have kids."
我沒有孩子”
為什么伊迪絲桑切斯不給她父親打電話
Why didn't Edith Sanchez call her father?
不好的后果
Negative consequence.
她父親很危險還是…
Is her father a danger?
一所學校
A school.
那不是一所學校 是嗎
It's not a school, is it?
那是
It's a...
一所監獄
It's a prison.
為什么
Why?
因為你
Because of you.
伊迪絲是擔心你
Edith was afraid for you.
擔心他們會傷害你
Afraid they would hurt you.
（合同已轉派）
（解除任務）
麥迪娜在民宿
Medina's at the Airbnb.
打電話給她 然后報警
Call her, then the police.
這么做明智嗎
Is that wise?
你的身份是聯邦監獄的逃犯
You're an escaped convict from a federal penitentiary.
還有別的事嗎
Anything else?
我們找到伊迪絲桑切斯了
We found Edith Sanchez.
雷金被殺不是因為他在找伊迪絲
Ray King wasn't murdered because he was looking for Edith.
而是因為他找到了她
He was murdered because he found her.
馬上打給瑪莉貝絲
Call Marybeth now.
告訴她我馬上到
Tell her I'm on my way.
還有 我們得找到伊迪絲的兒子阿爾貝托
And we need to find Edith's son Alberto.
他被當作囚犯關在華雷斯
He's being held as a prisoner in Juárez.
好的 克里斯 明白了
Okay, Chris. Understood.
喂
Hello?
有人要來殺你
Someone's coming to kill you.
瑪莉貝絲
Marybeth?
喂
Hello?
放下槍 放下槍
Drop it. Drop it!
轉過去
Turn around.
我是聯邦探員 你找錯人了
I'm a federal agent. Big mistake.
除非你的名字不是瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜
Only if your name is not Marybeth Medina.
舉起手
Hands!
雙膝跪地
Down on your knees.
快點
Now!
（西班牙語）媽媽 媽媽
?Mamá! ?Mami!
（西班牙語）別把我藏起來
（西班牙語）快點 該死的 好嗎
（西班牙語）別動
（西班牙語）不
?No!
你是伊迪絲桑切斯
You're Edith Sanchez.
早就不是了
Not anymore.
我想你兒子應該被關在 華雷斯的一處營地里
I think your child is a prisoner in a compound in Juárez.
沒事的
It's okay.
用手壓住傷口
I need to put pressure on this.
救援馬上到
Help is coming.
不 不 我付錢給你是讓你去殺她
No, no. I-I paid you to kill her,
不是聽你說失手
not to try and kill her.
有人介入了這次行動
Someone intervened in the hit.
是一個極度危險的家伙
An extraordinarily lethal someone.
我們的合約會一直生效
Our contracts are enforced until the target is dead
直到目標死亡或客戶死亡
or the client's expired.
祝你今晚愉快
Enjoy your evening.
去華雷斯
Go to Juárez.
帶那些孩子去沙漠
Take those kids into the desert.
解決他們 然后埋掉
I want 'em dead and buried.
別留痕跡
No trace.
別讓人追查到我
Nothing to tie me to them.
你覺得你能做到嗎
Think you can handle that?
好的 伯克
Yeah, Burke.
我能做到
Yeah, I can handle that.
你去到華雷斯 然后呢
You show up in Juárez, and then what?
你要怎么找到這些孩子
How you even gonna find these kids?
不用你擔心 你可以走了
Not your concern. You can leave.
真受不了 你要我告訴你多少次
For Christ's sake. How many times do I got to tell you?
麥迪娜的事不是我的錯 懂嗎
What happened to Medina was not my fault.
是她說不想跟我們扯上關系的
All right? She said she wanted nothing to do with us.
我照著做而已
I just... I took her at her word.
她的肺被刺穿了 脾臟破裂 下巴骨折
She has a punctured lung, ruptured spleen and a fractured jaw.
那就別給她送果籃了
So don't send an Edible Arrangement.
你說吧 多少次才夠
How many times? How many times I got to do it?
要我說多少次對不起才夠
How many times I got to say I'm sorry?
我不知道 你一次都沒說過
I don't know. You haven't said it one time.
你真會胡說八道
Ah, you're so full of shit.
一切都是因為照片里那該死的孩子 對吧
All this is about is about the goddamn kid in the picture, right?
你覺得他跟你很像
You think he's like you.
是的 他在華雷斯孤身一人
Yes. He's alone in Juárez.
-你會在乎嗎 -你怎么知道
- Do you even care? Do you... - How do you know that?
你怎么知道他跟你一樣
How do you know he's like you?
你太奇怪了 克里斯
You are so weird, Chris.
你腦子里的想法總是莫名其妙
You get these ideas in your head,
數不完的執念
and you just obsess...
該死的 知道這多讓人心累嗎
Goddamn it, you know how exhausting it is?
我這輩子都在給那個奇怪的孩子
My entire life, I've had to clean up
擦屁股 你知道嗎
after the weird kid, you know that?
我不奇怪
I'm not weird.
你不奇怪
Oh, you're not weird?
小時候我們每一次搬家
Every fucking time we move,
去到一個新城市 你都會發作 拽著拳頭
we go to a new town. What happens? Then you show up with your fits.
-我早就不那樣了 -不停唱那首愚蠢的童謠
- I don't do that anymore, Braxton. - Your rocking. Your stupid
《所羅門格蘭迪》
Solomon Grundy bullshit.
然后你被人欺負
Then I got to beat somebody's ass
我還得去揍他們替你出氣
'cause they put their hands on you.
不 你喜歡打架
No. You like to fight!
那根本不是重點
Ah, it ain't the goddamn point!
重點是
The point is
無論什么時候我都會挺你 克里斯
I always get your fucking back, Chris! - Goodbye.
我那么挺你 你說過一句謝謝嗎
I get your back. You ever say thank you?
哇 天啊 謝謝你 布萊斯頓
"Wow. Gee, thanks, Brax.
謝謝你一直那么挺我 謝謝
Thank you for getting my back. Thank you.
你是這世上最好的弟弟
You are the best goddamn brother..."
你干什么
What are you doing? You...
我被你氣死了
Goddamn it!
怎么 拍拍屁股走了
What, you just gonna leave?
該死的 我告訴你 要去華雷斯是吧
Fuck. You know what? You want to go to Juárez?
好呀 那就去華雷斯
Hey, let's go to Juárez.
這主意不錯 讓我們一起送人頭去吧
Good for you. Let's go get our asses shot off.
（海關與邊境保護局 亞利桑那州 塞拉維斯塔）
我的無人機沒有回應
My drone's not responding.
沒有反應
I lost the feed.
（墨西哥 一號無人機 二號無人機）
（西班牙語）快 快上車
Get 'em on. Get 'em on.
（華雷斯營地 墨西哥 華雷斯）
（西班牙語）快點 都上車 快點 快點
都上去 看著他們 都往后坐 動作快
Load 'em up, load 'em up. All the way to the back. Fill it up.
（西班牙語）速度快
Vámonos.
野外郊游 跟上他們 快上車 都上車
Field trip. Follow them. Get on the bus. Get 'em on.
動起來
Let's go!
所有人都出來 野外郊游 把他們帶上車
Everybody out! Field trip! Get 'em on the bus!
（正在繪制華雷斯營地地圖）
（完成）
你找到了
You found it?
（私密號碼）
我們找到了
We found it.
多遠
How far?
11分鐘車程
11 minutes.
好的
Okay.
我們等到天黑之后再進去
We'll wait till dark, and then we'll go in.
你能把燈關掉嗎
Can you kill the lights?
可以 但沒用
Yes, but it won't matter.
為什么
Why not?
不用等到天黑孩子們就都死了
The children will be dead before it's dark.
布萊斯頓
Braxton.
什么
Yeah.
謝謝你
Thank you.
讓他們都出來 嘿
Get 'em all out!
所有孩子都給我上車 野外郊游
Hey, all the kids on the bus! Field trip!
（西班牙語）快點 動作快
Rápido.
（西班牙語）動作快 臭小子 動起來
- ?Qué me ven, cabrones? - Get 'em all out!
讓他們都出來 快點
- Muévanse. Ey, ey. - Let's go!
（西班牙語）嘿 嘿 動作快
Rápido.
都出來了嗎 所有人
（西班牙語）有人來了 有人來了
（西班牙語）快點 動起來 混蛋
（西班牙語）快點
（西班牙語）快 出來
（西班牙語）他跑了 他跑了 往那兒跑了
嘿 給他們點顏色
Hey! Move on them!
給我守住了 我馬上就回來
Hold it down! I'll be right back!
你在哪兒 臭小子
Where you at, kid?
你死去哪里了
Where the fuck are you?
嘿 小子 你在哪里
Hey, kid, where you at?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你躲在這里干嗎 想害死我嗎 快點
The fuck do you think you're doing? You trying to get me killed? Get up!
趕緊走 快點 這邊 這邊
We're moving. Come on. This way, this way.
快走
Go.
快回擊 還不趴下 真是蠢貨
Fire back! Get down, you dumb motherfucker!
（西班牙語）快點 快點
趕緊開車
Start the bus!
（西班牙語）快 混蛋 快
快走
Go!
（西班牙語）混蛋
（西班牙語）去死吧
手榴彈 克里斯 快走
Fire, Chris! Go, go!
（校車）
讓開 讓開 讓開
Move, move, move, move, move! Move!
（西班牙語）讓開 閉嘴
-你中彈了 -我沒事 嘿
- You're hit? - I'm good. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
我沒事 快走
I'm good. Go.
-我沒事 不 我沒事 嘿 停下 -你中槍了
- I'm fine, go. I'm fine. Hey, stop. - No. You're hit.
你快去救人 這些混蛋我能應付 快走
Finish the fucking job. I-I got these motherfuckers. Just go!
快走 克里斯 去救那些孩子 走啊
Go, Chris. Go get to those kids! Go! Damn it.
（西班牙語）該死的
（西班牙語）你完蛋了
先等等
Now, wait.
（西班牙語）去地獄里等我吧 伙計
等等
Wait.
我們走
Let's go.
（西班牙語）不 別亂動
我得包扎傷口
I need to seal it.
動作快 讓他們趕緊下車
Open up! Help them off the bus.
（西班牙語）快 快 快
快下車 趕緊把事辦完
Get off the bus. Let's get this over with.
快走 快
Come on. Move. Hey.
（西班牙語）動作快
?ándale!
（西班牙語）快 下車
都給我滾到坑里去
Get in the fucking hole!
都到坑里去 快 動作快
Get in the hole now! Hurry up!
快點 快點 跟著你們前面的人
Move! Move! Follow the person in front of you.
快點
Go!
（西班牙語）快點
-快點 跟上前面的 -跟上前面的
Come on. Follow them. Follow them.
（西班牙語）快點 快走
到那兒去 到那邊去
動作快
Go. Hurry up.
（西班牙語）快 跑快點 跑快點 動作快
（西班牙語）快點 快點 動起來 動起來
Move!
該死
又是你 又是你 起來
You again? You again? Hey, get up.
嘿 退后 該死的退后
Hey, back up. Back the fuck up!
所羅門格蘭迪
Solomon Grundy,
-我只是替老板做事 -星期一降人世
- born on a Monday. - Hey, I got a heavy figure!
星期二把名賜
Christened on Tuesday.
-我不是你要找的人 -星期三結連理
- I'm not the guy you want. - Married on Wednesday.
-你要找的人是伯克 -星期四染病疾
- Burke is the guy you want. - Sick on Thursday.
-聽我說 伙計 -星期五病加劇
- Worse on Friday. - Listen to me, man!
星期六命歸西
Died on Saturday.
-聽到沒有 -星期日葬入泥
- Listen to me! - Buried on Sunday.
伯克才是那個…
Burke is the guy...
這就是所羅門格蘭迪的一生
That was the end of Solomon Grundy.
阿爾貝托桑切斯
Alberto Sanchez?
沒事了
It's okay.
（西班牙語）沒事了
Estás bien.
（西班牙語）你安全了 沒事了
Estás seguro. Estás bien.
你們安全了
You're safe.
沒事了
It's okay.
（西班牙語）你們都安全了
Estás a salvo.
我們走了 好嗎
Let's go, yeah?
（西班牙語）我們走吧
Vámonos.
沒事的
It's okay.
別看他 到車上去 好嗎
Just go... go over to the bus, yeah?
我們走 沒事了
Let's go. It's okay.
不用管這些 走吧
我們走 到車上去 很好
前面是誰
Who's that?
嘿 克里斯 停一下車
Hey, Chris, stop the bus.
-什么 -停一下車 快點 伙計
- What? - Stop the bus, man. Just...
開下門
Open the door.
開下門 大哥
Open the door, ding-dong.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
到這兒來
Come here.
嘿
Hey.
嗨 你是誰
Hi. Who are you?
嗨
Hi.
克里斯
Chris.
她喜歡我 兄弟
She likes me, man.
想不想跟我回家
You want to... You want to come home with me?
克里斯
Chris.
嘿
Hey.
看看這小丫頭
Look at her.
好了 做我的小貓咪好嗎
Yeah. Are you gonna be mine?
我就和你說吧
As I suspected.
給她取什么名字好呢
What do you think, man? What should I call her?
它是…
That's a...
它是公的
That's a male
貓咪
cat.
（捷克共和國 布拉格老城區）
（俄羅斯語）喂
Da.
巴圖頓涅茨克
Batu Donetsk,
歐洲最大的殺手組織的老板
owner of the largest kill squad in Europe?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你應該是把我和別人搞混了
You have me confused with someone else.
52歲
52 years old.
出生于下諾夫哥羅德
Born in Nizhny Novgorod.
有俄羅斯 羅馬尼亞和蒙古族血統
Russian, Romanian, Mongol descent.
在人稱黑海豚的監獄服刑七年
Seven years in the prison known as the Black Dolphin.
結過四次婚
Married four times.
和情婦有一個孩子
One child by a mistress.
需要我告訴你 你的賓利跑了多少里程嗎
Would you like me to tell you the mileage on your Bentley?
有什么能為你效勞的
What can I do for you?
終止暗殺瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜的任務
Terminate the contract on Marybeth Medina.
我為什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
我來給你講個故事
Let me tell you a story.
（韓語）您還要點些什么嗎
（韓語）你們有什么甜品
（韓語）我們有冰激凌和蜜油果子
Ice cream...
（韓語）蜜油果子很不錯
（韓語）如果是新鮮出爐的 給我來一個蜜油果子
（韓語）好的
（韓語）麻煩 點單
（私密號碼來電）
說話
Speak.
哥斯達黎加 瓜納卡斯特省
Guanacaste Province, Costa Rica.
寫下來
Write it down.
（哥斯達黎加 瓜納卡斯特省）
我勸你還是干好你的工作
How about you do your fucking job
遵守你的合約 好嗎
and stick to the contract?
你說過合約將一直有效
You said the contract would stay in place
直到財政部那女人死了為止
until that Treasury bitch was dead.
又或者是你死了 對嗎
Or until you expired. Correct?
謝謝 我現在活得好好的
Well, I am very much alive.
那就按合約辦
Consider it done.
很好 什么時候
Good. When?
快了 先生
Momentarily, sir.
再見
Goodbye.
是你
What?
（55號泊位 海鮮魚市和熟食）
謝謝
Thanks.
先生們 你們好嗎
Gentlemen. How are you?
很高興見到你們
Nice to see you.
副局長 您還好嗎
Deputy Director. You doing okay?
是的 好得差不多了
Yeah, I'm feeling pretty good.
多謝關心
局長
哈伯神經科學學院
Harbor Neuroscience Academy.
我是財政部的麥迪娜副局長
This is Deputy Director Medina, U.S. Treasury.
女士 我想您應該是撥錯號碼了
Ma'am, I don't think you're calling who you think you are.
我沒打錯
I think I am.
我知道你聽得到
I know you can hear me.
我只是想說一聲謝謝
And I just wanted to say thank you.
雷找到了伊迪絲 但是你和克里斯
Ray found Edith, but you and Chris helped me
幫我解開了剩下的謎題
solve the rest of the puzzle.
雷會很感激的
Ray would be grateful.
我也是
And so am I.
怎么樣 艾登
Is that good, Aidan?
不錯 好的
Uh, yeah, it looks good.
很棒
Awesome.
她來了 快點 走吧 邁爾斯
Oh, she's here. Come on. Let's go, Miles.
-走吧 現在 -現在嗎
- Going. Let's go. - Going now?
等一下
Hold on.
好的
Yeah.
（歡迎你 阿爾貝托）
（送去金融犯罪執法局 瑪莉貝絲麥迪娜收）
這孩子真了不起
Kid's unbelievable.
布萊斯頓
Braxton.
這也太不公平了
It's-it's-it's... It's wildly unfair.
他是個孩子 布萊斯頓
He's a child, Braxton.
誰在乎他是不是孩子 我是大人 你是大人
I don't care he's a child. I'm a man. You're a man.
他是孩子 那是貓 那又怎樣
He's a kid. That's a cat. Who cares?
重點是我們應該輪流才對
The point is we're supposed to be taking turns.
他抱著我的貓已經一個半小時了 克里斯
He's been holding my cat for the last hour and a half, Chris.
什么時候才輪到我
So when's it my turn?
還要開多久
How much longer, man?
（西班牙語）阿貝爾托 還要多久到哈伯
Alberto. ?Cuánto falta hasta Harbor?
（西班牙語）1247英里
Mil doscientas cuarenta y siete millas.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
還要1247英里
Uh, 1,247 miles.
我真是服了 算這些他倒是算得飛快
It's amazing. It's amazing how he can just come up with that
但他卻算不清楚
but he can't figure out how long it takes
多久該輪到別人抱小貓咪
to give somebody else a turn holding the damn cat.
真是個該死的天才
He's like a freaking genius.
我只是好奇問問
Just, um, out of idle curiosity,
你有什么計劃嗎 等把這孩子送到哈伯后
what are your plans after, uh... after we drop Alberto at Harbor?
我的計劃
My plans?
我沒想過
I-I don't know.
是這樣 那個…
Do you think, um...
我在房車公園預訂了位置 就在查塔胡奇
Well, I made a reservation at an RV park, uh,
等我們送完阿爾貝托
at the Chattahoochee for after we drop off Alberto,
我想我們可以去那里徒步
a-and I thought we could go hiking there.
你訂了位置
You-you made a reservation?
只是個提議
It's just an idea.
然后 我們就住那房車里
And-and what, we'd... we-we'd stay in the Airstream?
對 會很有意思
I think it'll be fun.
-沒錯 我也覺得會很有意思 -那就好
I think it... I think it might be fun, too.
（導演 加文奧康納）
（編劇 比爾迪比克）
（攝影 謝默斯麥加維）
（音樂 布萊斯戴斯納）
（本阿弗萊克飾克里斯/克里斯蒂安）
（喬恩伯恩瑟爾飾布萊斯頓）
（辛西婭阿戴-羅賓遜飾瑪莉貝絲）
（丹妮拉皮內達飾艾妮絲）
（艾莉森羅伯遜飾賈絲廷）
（羅伯特摩根飾伯克）
（J.K.西蒙斯飾雷金）
（進口 中國電影集團公司）
（發行 中國電影股份有限公司 華夏電影發行有限責任公司）
（譯制 上海電影（集團）公司 上海電影譯制廠）
（譯制職員 翻譯 夏恬）